<story>The Lady of the House of Love 
    At last the revenants became so troublesome the peasants
    abandoned the village and it fell solely into the possession of subtle and vindictive
    inhabitants who manifest their presences by shadows that fall almost imperceptibly awry, too
    many shadows, even at midday, <irrational_existence>shadows that have no source in anything
        visible; by the sound, sometimes, of sobbing in a derelict bedroom where a cracked mirror
        suspended from a wall does not reflect a presence; by a sense of unease that will afflict
        the travleller unwise enough to pause</irrational_existence> to drink from the fountain in
    the square that still gushes spring water from a faucet stuck in a stone lion's mouth. A cat
    prowls in a weedy garden; he grins and spits, arches his back, bounces away from an intangible
    on four fear-stiffened legs. Now all shun the village below the chateau in which <trapped>the
        beautiful somnambulist helplessly perpetuates her ancestral crimes</trapped>. Wearing an
    antique bridal gown, the beautiful queen of the vampires sits <trapped>all alone in her dark,
        high house under the eyes of the portraits of her demented and atrocious ancestors, each one
        of whom, through her, <irrational_existence>projects a baleful posthumous
            existence</irrational_existence>;</trapped> she counts out the Tarot cards, ceaselessly
    construing a constellation of possibilities as if the random fall of the cards on the red plush
    tablecloth before her could precipitate her from her chill, shuttered room into a country of
    perpetual summer and obliterate <irrational_existence>the perennial sadness of a girl who is
        both death and the maiden</irrational_existence>. Her voice is filled with distant
    sonorities, like reverberations in a cave: now you are at the place of annihilation, now you are
    at the place of annihilation. And she is herself a cave full of echoes, <trapped>she is a system
        of repetitions, she is a closed circuit.'</trapped> Can a bird sing only the song it knows
    or can it learn a new song?' She draws her long, sharp fingernail across the bars of the cage in
    which her pet lark sings, striking a plangent twang like that of the plucked heartstrings of a
    woman of metal. Her hair falls down like tears. The castle is mostly given over to ghostly
    occupants but she herself has her own suite of drawing room and bedroom. Closely barred shutters
    and heavy velvet curtains keep out every leak of natural light. There is a round table on a
    single leg covered with a red plush cloth on which she lays out her inevitable Tarot; this room
    is never more than faintly illuminated by a heavily shaded lamp on the mantelpiece and the dark
    red figured wallpaper is obscurely, distressingly patterned by the rain that drives in through
    the neglected roof and leaves behind it random areas of staining, ominous marks like those left
    on the sheets by dead lovers. Depredations of rot and fungus everywhere. The unlit chandelier is
    so heavy with dust the individual prisms no longer show any shapes; industrious spiders have
    woven canopies in the corners of this ornate and rotting place, have trapped the porcelain vases
    on the mantelpiece in soft grey nets. But the mistress of all this disintegration notices
    nothing. She sits in a chair covered in moth-ravaged burgundy velvet at the low, round table and
    distributes the cards; sometimes the lark sings, but more often remains a sullen mound of drab
    feathers. <trapped>Sometimes the Countess will wake it for a brief cadenza by strumming the bars
        of its cage; she likes to hear it announce how it cannot escape.</trapped>
    <irrational_existence>She rises when the sun sets</irrational_existence> and goes immediately to
    her table where she plays her game of patience until she grows hungry, until she becomes
    ravenous. <beauty_mask>She is so beautiful she is unnatural; her beauty is an abnormality, a
        deformity,</beauty_mask> for none of her features exhibit any of those touching
    imperfections that reconcile us to the imperfection of the human condition. <beauty_mask>Her
        beauty is a symptom of her disorder, of her soullessness.</beauty_mask> The white hands of
    the tenebrous belle deal the hand of destiny. Her fingernails are longer than those of the
    mandarins of ancient China and each is pared to a fine point. These and <trapped>teeth as fine
        and white as spikes of spun sugar are the visible signs of the destiny she wistfully
        attempts to evade via the arcana;</trapped> her claws a<roses>nd teeth have been sharpened
        on centuries of corpses,</roses>
    <roses>she is the last bud of the poison tree that sprang from the loins of Vlad the
        Impaler</roses> who picnicked on corpses in the forests of Transylvania. The walls of her
    bedroom are hung with black satin, embroidered with <trapped>tears of pearl</trapped>. At the
    room's four corners are funerary urns and bowls which emit slumbrous, pungent fumes of incense.
    In the centre is an elaborate catafalque, in ebony, surrounded by long candles in enormous
    silver candlesticks. In a white lace négligé stained a little with blood, the
        <irrational_existence>Countess climbs up on her catafalque at dawn each morning and lies
        down in an open coffin.</irrational_existence> A chignoned priest of the Orthodox faith
    staked out her wicked father at a Carpathian crossroad before her milk teeth grew. Just as they
    staked him out, the fatal Count cried: 'Nosferatu is dead; long live Nosferatu!' Now she
    possesses all the haunted forests and mysterious habitations of his vast domain; she is the
    hereditary commandant of the army of shadows who camp in the village below her chateau, who
    penetrate the woods in the form of owls, bats and foxes, who make the milk curdle and the butter
    refuse to come, who ride the horses all night on a wild hunt so they are sacks of skin and bone
    in the morning, who milk the cows dry and, especially, torment pubescent girls with fainting
    fits, disorders of the blood, diseases of the imagination. <trapped>But the Countess herself is
        indifferent to her own weird authority, as if she were dreaming it. In her dream, she would
        like to be human; but she does not know if that is possible.</trapped> The Tarot always
    shows the same configuration: always she turns up La Papesse, La Mort, La Tour Abolie, wisdom,
    death, dissolution. On moonless nights, her keeper lets her out into the garden. <roses>This
        garden, an exceedingly sombre place, bears a strong resemblance to a burial ground and all
        the roses her dead mother planted have grown up into a huge, spiked wall that incarcerates
        her in the castle of her inheritance.</roses> When the back door opens, the Countess will
    sniff the air and howl. She drops, now, on all fours. Crouching, quivering, she catches the
    scent of her prey. Delicious crunch of the fragile bones of rabbits and small, furry things she
    pursues with fleet, four-footed speed; she will creep home, whimpering, with blood smeared on
    her cheeks. She pours water from the ewer in her bedroom into the bowl, she washes her face with
    the wincing, fastidious gestures of a cat. The voracious margin of huntress's nights in the
    gloomy garden, crouch and pounce, surrounds her habitual tormented somnambulism,
        <irrational_existence>her life or imitation of life.</irrational_existence> The eyes of this
    nocturnal creature enlarge and glow. All claws and teeth, she strikes, she gorges; <trapped>but
        nothing can console her for the ghastliness of her condition, nothing.</trapped> She resorts
    to the magic comfort of the Tarot pack and shuffles the cards, lays them out, reads them,
    gathers them up with a sigh, shu<irrational_existence>ffles them again, constantly constructing
        hypotheses about a future which is irreversible. An old mute looks after her, to make sure
        she never sees the sun, that all day she stays in her coffin</irrational_existence>, to keep
    mirrors and all reflective surfaces away from her--in short, to perform all the functions of the
    servants of vampires. Everything about this beautiful and ghastly lady is as it should be, queen
    of night, queen of terror--except <trapped>her horrible reluctance for the role.</trapped>
    Nevertheless, if an unwise adventurer pauses in the square of the deserted village to refresh
    himself at the fountain, a crone in a black dress and white apron presently emerges from a
    house. <sexless_temptress>She will invite you with smiles and gestures; you will follow her. The
        Countess wants fresh meat.</sexless_temptress> When she was a little girl, she was like a
    fox and contented herself entirely with baby rabbits that squeaked piteously as she bit into
    their necks with a nauseated voluptuousness, with voles and field-mice that palpitated for a
    bare moment between her embroidress's fingers. But now she is a woman, she must have men. If you
    stop too long beside the giggling fountain, you will be led by the hand to the Countess's
    larder. All day, she lies in her coffin in her négligé of <spilling_blood>blood-stained
        lace</spilling_blood>. When the sun drops behind the mountain, she yawns and stirs and puts
    on the only dress she has, her mother's wedding dress, to sit and read her cards until she grows
    hungry. <trapped>She loathes the food she eats; she would have liked to take the rabbits home
        with her, feed them on lettuce, pet them and make them a nest</trapped> in her red-and-black
    chinoiserie escritoire, <sexless_temptress>but hunger always overcomes her</sexless_temptress>.
    She sinks her teeth into the neck where an artery throbs with fear; <trapped>she will drop the
        deflated skin from which she has extracted all the nourishment with a small cry of both pain
        and disgust</trapped>. And it is the same with the shepherd boys and gipsy lads who,
    ignorant or foolhardy, come to wash the dust from their feet in the water of the fountain; the
    Countess's governess brings them into the drawing room where the cards on the table always show
    the Grim Reaper. The Countess herself will serve them coffee in tiny cracked, precious cups, and
    little sugar cakes. The hobbledehoys sit with a spilling cup in one hand and a biscuit in the
    other, gaping at the Countess in her satin finery as she pours from a silver pot and chatters
    distractedly to put them at their fatal ease. A certain desolate stillness of her eyes indicates
    she is inconsolable. She would like to caress their lean brown cheeks and stroke their ragged
    hair. When she takes them by the hand and leads them to her bedroom, they can scarcely believe
    their luck. Afterwards, her governess will tidy the remains into a neat pile and wrap it in its
    own discarded clothes. This mortal parcel she then discreetly buries in the garden.
        <spilling_blood>The blood on the Countess's cheeks will be mixed with
    tears</spilling_blood>; her keeper probes her fingernails for her with a little silver
    toothpick, to get rid of the fragments of skin and bone that have lodged there Fee fie fo film I
    smell the blood of an Englishman. One hot, ripe summer in the pubescent years of the present
    century, a young officer in the British army, blond, blue-eyed, heavy-muscled, visiting friends
    in Vienna, decided to spend the remainder of his furlough exploring the little-known uplands of
    Romania. When he quixotically decided to travel the rutted cart-tracks by bicycle, he saw all
    the humour of it: 'on two wheels in the land of the vampires'. So, laughing, he sets out on his
    adventure. <foreshadowing>He has the special quality of virginity, most and least ambiguous of
        states: ignorance, yet at the same time, power in potentia,</foreshadowing> and,
    furthermore, unknowingness, which is not the same as ignorance. He is more than he knows--and
    has about him, besides, the special glamour of that generation for whom history has already
    prepared a special, exemplary fate in the trenches of France. This being, rooted in change and
    time, is about to collide with the timeless Gothic eternity of the <foreshadowing>vampires, for
        whom all is as it has always been and will be, whose cards always fall in the same
        pattern.</foreshadowing>
    <foreshadowing>Although so young, he is also rational.</foreshadowing> He has chosen the most
    rational mode of transport in the world for his trip round the Carpathians. <foreshadowing>To
        ride a bicycle is in itself some protection against superstitious fears, since the bicycle
        is the product of pure reason applied to motion.</foreshadowing> Geometry at the service of
    man! Give me two spheres and a straight line and I will show you how far I can take them.
    Voltaire himself might have invented the bicycle, since it contributes so much to man's welfare
    and nothing at all to his bane. Beneficial to the health, it emits no harmful fumes and permits
    only the most decorous speeds. How can a bicycle ever be an implement of harm? A single kiss
    woke up the Sleeping Beauty in the Wood. The waxen fingers of the Countess, fingers of a holy
    image, turn up the card called Les Amoureux. Never, never before ... <sexless_temptress>never
        before has the Countess cast herself a fate involving love</sexless_temptress>. She shakes,
    she trembles, her great eyes close beneath her finely veined, nervously fluttering eyelids;
            <sexless_temptress><foreshadowing>the lovely cartomancer has, this time, the first time,
            dealt herself a hand of love and death</foreshadowing></sexless_temptress>. Be he alive
    or be he dead I'll grind his bones to make my bread. At the mauvish beginnings of evening, the
    English m'sieu toils up the hill to the village he glimpsed from a great way off; he must
    dismount and push his bicycle before him, the path too steep to ride. He hopes to find a
    friendly inn to rest the night; he's hot, hungry, thirsty, weary, dusty ... At first, such
    disappointment, to discover the roofs of all the cottages caved in and tall weeds thrusting
    through the piles of fallen tiles, shutters hanging disconsolately from their hinges, an
    entirely uninhabited place. And the rank vegetation whispers, as if foul secrets, here, where,
    if one were sufficiently imaginative, one could almost imagine twisted faces appearing
    momentarily beneath the crumbling eaves ... but the adventure of it all, and the consolation of
    the poignant brightness of the hollyhocks still bravely blooming in the shaggy gardens, and the
    beauty of the flaming sunset, all these considerations soon overcame his disappointment, even
    assuaged the faint unease he'd felt. And the fountain where the village women used to wash their
    clothes still gushed out bright, clear water; he gratefully washed his feet and hands, applied
    his mouth to the faucet, then let the icy stream run over his face. When he raised his dripping,
    gratified head from the lion's mouth, he saw, silently arrived beside him in the square, an old
    woman who smiled eagerly, almost conciliatorily at him. She wore a black dress and a white
    apron, with a housekeeper's key ring at the waist; her grey hair was neatly coiled in a chignon
    beneath the white linen headdress worn by elderly women of that region. She bobbed a curtsy at
    the young man and beckoned him to follow her. When he hesitated, she pointed towards the great
    bulk of the mansion above them, whose façade loured over the village, rubbed her stomach,
    pointed to her mouth, rubbed her stomach again, clearly miming an invitation to supper. Then she
    beckoned him again, this time turning determinedly upon her heel as though she would brook no
    opposition. <roses>A great, intoxicated surge of the heavy scent of red roses blew into his face
        as soon as they left the village, inducing a sensuous vertigo; a blast of rich,
            <foreshadowing>faintly corrupt sweetness strong enough almost, to fell
            him</foreshadowing>.</roses>
    <roses>Too many roses. Too many roses bloomed on enormous thickets that lined the path, thickets
        bristling with thorns, and the flowers themselves were almost too luxuriant, their huge
        congregations of plush petals somehow obscene in their excess, their whorled, tightly budded
        cores outrageous in their implications.</roses> The mansion emerged grudgingly out of this
    jungle. In the subtle and haunting light of the setting sun, that golden light rich with
    nostalgia for the day that is just past, the sombre visage of the place, part manor house, part
    fortified farmhouse, immense, rambling, a dilapidated eagle's nest atop the crag down which its
    attendant village meandered, reminded him of childhood tales on winter evenings, when he and his
    brothers and sisters scared themselves half out of their wits with ghost stories set in just
    such places and then had to have candles to light them up newly terrifying stairs to bed. He
    could almost have regretted accepting the crone's unspoken invitation; but now, standing before
    the door of time-eroded oak while she selected a huge iron key from the clanking ringful at her
    waist, he knew it was too late to turn back and brusquely reminded himself he was no child, now,
    to be frightened of his own fancies. The old lady unlocked the door, which swung back on
    melodramatically creaking hinges, and fussily took charge of his bicycle, in spite of his
    protests. He felt a certain involuntary <foreshadowing>sinking of the heart to see his beautiful
        two-wheeled symbol of rationality vanish into the dark entrails of the
        mansion</foreshadowing>, to, no doubt, some damp outhouse where they would not oil it or
    check its tyres. But, in for a penny, in for a pound--in his youth and strength and blond
    beauty, in the invisible, even unacknowledged pentacle of his virginity, the young man stepped
    over the threshold of Nosferatu's castle and did not shiver in the blast of cold air, as from
    the mouth of a grave, that emanated from the lightless, cavernous interior. The crone took him
    to a little chamber where there was a black oak table spread with a clean white cloth and this
    cloth was carefully laid with heavy silverware, a little tarnished, as if someone with foul
    breath had breathed on it, but laid with one place only. Curiouser and curiouser; invited to the
    castle for dinner, now he must dine alone. All the same, he sat down as she had bid him.
    Although it was not yet dark outside, the curtains were closely drawn and only the sparing light
    trickling from a single oil lamp showed him how dismal his surroundings were. The crone bustled
    about to get him a bottle of wine and a glass from an ancient cabinet of wormy oak; while he
    bemusedly drank his wine, she disappeared but soon returned bearing a steaming platter of the
    local spiced meat stew with dumplings, and a shank of black bread. He was hungry after his long
    day's ride, he ate heartily and polished his plate with the crust, but this coarse food was
    hardly the entertainment he'd expected from the gentry and he was puzzled by the assessing glint
    in the dumb woman's eyes as she watched him eating. But she darted off to get him a second
    helping as soon as he'd finished the first one and she seemed so friendly and helpful, besides,
    that he knew he could count on a bed for the night in the castle, as well as his supper, so he
    sharply reprimanded himself for his own childish lack of enthusiasm for the eerie silence, the
    clammy chill of the place. When he'd put away the second plateful, the old woman came and
    gestured he should leave the table and follow her once again. She made a pantomime of drinking;
    he deduced he was now invited to take after- dinner coffee in another room with some more
    elevated member of the household who had not wished to dine with him but, all the same, wanted
    to make his acquaintance. An honour, no doubt; in deference to his host's opinion of himself, he
    straightened his tie, brushed the crumbs from his tweed jacket. He was surprised to find how
    ruinous the interior of the house was--cobwebs, worm-eaten beams, crumbling plaster; but the
    mute crone resolutely wound him on the reel of her lantern down endless corridors, up winding
    staircases, through the galleries where the painted eyes of family portraits briefly flickered
    as they passed, eyes that belonged, he noticed, to faces, one and all, of a quite memorable
    beastliness. At last she paused and, behind the door where they'd halted, he heard a faint,
    metallic twang as of, perhaps, a chord struck on a harpsichord. And then, wonderfully, the
    liquid cascade of the song of a lark, bringing to him, in the heart--had he but known it--of
        <beauty_mask>Juliet's tomb</beauty_mask>, all the freshness of morning.The crone rapped with
    her knuckles on the panels; <sexless_temptress>the most seductively caressing voice he had ever
        heard in his life softly called out, in heavily accented French</sexless_temptress>, the
    adopted language of the Romanian aristocracy: 'Entrez.' First of all, he saw only a shape, a
    shape imbued with a faint luminosity since it caught and reflected in its yellowed surfaces what
    little light there was in the ill-lit room; this shape resolved itself into that of, of all
    things, a hoop-skirted dress of white satin draped here and there with lace, a dress fifty or
    sixty years out of fashion but once, obviously, intended for a wedding. <beauty_mask>And then he
        saw the girl who wore the dress, a girl with the fragility of the skeleton of a moth, so
        thin, so frail that her dress seemed to him to hang suspended</beauty_mask>, as if
    untenanted in the dank air, a fabulous lending, a self-articulated garment in which she lived
    like a ghost in a machine. All the light in the room came from a low-burning lamp with a thick
    greenish shade on a distant mantelpiece; the crone who accompanied him shielded her lantern with
    her hand, as if to protect her mistress from too suddenly seeing, or their guest from too
    suddenly seeing her. So that it was <beauty_mask>little by little, as his eyes grew accustomed
        to the half-dark, that he saw how beautiful and how very young the bedizened scarecrow
        was</beauty_mask>, and he thought of a child dressing up in her mother's clothes, perhaps a
    child putting on the clothes of a dead mother in order to bring her, however briefly, to life
    again. The Countess stood behind a low table, <trapped>beside a pretty, silly, gilt-and-wire
        birdcage, hands outstretched in a distracted attitude that was almost one of
        flight</trapped>; she looked as startled by their entry as if she had not requested it. With
    her stark white face, <beauty_mask>her lovely death's head surrounded by long dark hair that
        fell down as straight as if it were soaking wet, <trapped>she looked like a shipwrecked
            bride</trapped>.</beauty_mask>
    <sexless_temptress>Her huge dark eyes almost broke his heart with their waiflike, lost look; yet
        he was disturbed, almost repelled, by her extraordinarily fleshy mouth</sexless_temptress>,
    a mouth with wide, full, prominent lips of a vibrant purplish-crimson, <sexless_temptress>a
        morbid mouth</sexless_temptress>. Even--but he put the thought away from him
        immediately--<sexless_temptress>a whore's mouth</sexless_temptress>. She shivered all the
    time, a starveling chill, a malarial agitation of the bones. He thought she must be only sixteen
    or seventeen years old, no more, <beauty_mask>with the hectic, unhealthy beauty of a
        consumptive. She was the chatelaine of all this decay.</beauty_mask>
    <irrational_existence>With many tender precautions, the crone now raised the light she held to
        show his hostess her guest's face. At that, the Countess let out a faint, mewing cry and
        made a blind, appalled gesture with her hands, as if pushing him
    away</irrational_existence>, so that she knocked against the table and a butterfly dazzle of
    painted cards fell to the floor. Her mouth formed a round' o' of woe, she swayed a little and
    then sank into her chair, where she lay as if now scarcely capable of moving. A bewildering
    reception. Tsk'ing under her breath, the crone busily poked about on the table until she found
    an enormous pair of dark green glasses, such as blind beggars wear, and perched them on the
    Countess's nose. He went forward to pick up her cards for her from a carpet that, he saw to his
    surprise, was part rotted away, partly encroached upon by all kinds of virulent-looking fungi.
    He retrieved the cards and shuffled them carelessly together, for they meant nothing to him,
    though they seemed strange playthings for a young girl. What a grisly picture of a capering
    skeleton! He covered it up with a happier one--of two young lovers, smiling at one another, and
    put her toys back into a hand so slender you could almost see the frail net of bone beneath the
    translucent skin, a hand with fingernails as long, as finely pointed, as banjo picks. At his
    touch, she seemed to revive a little and almost smiled, raising herself upright. 'Coffee,' she
    said. 'You must have coffee.' And scooped up her cards into a pile so that the crone could set
    before her a silver spirit kettle, a silver coffee pot, cream jug, sugar basin, cups ready on a
    silver tray, a strange touch of elegance, even if discoloured, in this devastated interior whose
    mistress ethereally shone as if with her own blighted, submarine radiance. The crone found him a
    chair and, tittering noiselessly, departed, leaving the room a little darker. While the young
    lady attended to the coffee-making, he had time to contemplate with some distaste a further
        <trapped>series of family portraits which decorated the stained and peeling walls of the
        room; these livid faces all seemed contorted with a febrile madness and the blubber lips,
        the huge, demented eyes that all had in common bore a disquieting resemblance to those of
        the hapless victim of inbreeding</trapped> now patiently filtering her fragrant brew, even
    if some rare grace has so finely transformed those features when it came to her case. The lark,
    its chorus done, had long ago fallen silent; no sound but the chink of silver on china. Soon,
    she held out to him a tiny cup of rose-painted china. 'Welcome,' she said in her voice with the
    rushing sonorities of the ocean in it, <irrational_existence>a voice that seemed to come
        elsewhere than from her white, still throat.</irrational_existence> 'Welcome to my chateau.
    I rarely receive visitors and that's a misfortune since nothing animates me half as much as the
    presence of a stranger ... <trapped>This place is so lonely,</trapped> now the village is
    deserted, and my one companion, alas, she cannot speak. Often I am so silent that I think I,
    too, will soon forget how to do so <trapped>and nobody here will ever talk any more</trapped>.'
    She offered him a sugar biscuit from a Limoges plate; her fingernails struck carillons from the
    antique china. <roses>Her voice, issuing from those red lips like the obese roses in her garden,
        lips that do not move</roses>--her voice is curiously disembodied; she is like a doll, he
    thought, a ventriloquist's doll, or, more, like a great, ingenious piece of clockwork.
            <trapped><irrational_existence>For she seemed inadequately powered by some slow energy
            of which she was not in control; as if she had been wound up years ago, when she was
            born, and now the mechanism was inexorably running down and would leave her
            lifeless.</irrational_existence></trapped> This idea that <trapped>she might be an
        automaton, made of white velvet and black fur, that could not move of its own accord, never
        quite deserted him</trapped>; indeed, it deeply moved his heart. The carnival air of her
    white dress emphasized her unreality, like a sad Columbine who lost her way in the wood a long
    time ago and never reached the fair. 'And the light. I must apologize for the lack of light ...
    a hereditary affliction of the eyes ...' Her blind spectacles gave him his handsome face back to
    himself twice over; if he presented himself to her naked face, he would dazzle her like the sun
    she is forbidden to look at because it would shrivel her up at once, poor night bird, poor
    butcher bird. Vous serez ma proie. You have such a fine throat, m'sieu, like a column of marble.
    When you came through the door retaining about you all the golden light of the summer's day of
    which I know nothing, nothing, the card called 'Les Amoureux' had just emerged from the tumbling
    chaos of imagery before me; it seemed to me you had stepped off the card into my darkness and,
    for a moment, I thought, perhaps, you might irradiate it. I do not mean to hurt you. I shall
    wait for you in my bride's dress in the dark. The bridegroom is come, he will go into the
    chamber which has been prepared for him. I am condemned to solitude and dark; I do not mean to
    hurt you. I will be very gentle. (And could love free me from the shadows? Can a bird sing only
    the song it knows, or can it learn a new song?) S<sexless_temptress>ee, how I'm ready for you.
        I've always been ready for you; I've been waiting for you in my wedding dress, why have you
        delayed for so long ... it will all be over very quickly.</sexless_temptress> You will feel
    no pain, my darling. <trapped>She herself is a haunted house. She does not possess herself; her
        ancestors sometimes come and peer out of the windows of her eyes and that is very
        frightening</trapped>. <irrational_existence>She has the mysterious solitude of ambiguous
        states; she hovers in a no-man's land between life and death, sleeping and waking, behind
        the hedge of spiked flowers</irrational_existence>, Nosferatu's sanguinary
        <roses>rosebud</roses>.<trapped> The beastly forebears on the walls condemn her to a
        perpetual repetition of their passions.</trapped> (One kiss, however, and only one, woke up
    the Sleeping Beauty in the Wood.) Nervously, to conceal her inner voices, she keeps up a front
    of inconsequential chatter in French while her ancestors leer and grimace on the walls;
            <sexless_temptress><foreshadowing>however hard she tries to think of any other, she only
            knows of one kind of consummation</foreshadowing></sexless_temptress>. He was struck,
    once again, by the birdlike, predatory claws which tipped her marvellous hands;
        <irrational_existence>the sense of strangeness that had been growing on him since he buried
        his head under the streaming water in the village, since he entered the dark portals of the
        fatal castle, now fully overcame him.</irrational_existence> Had he been a cat, he would
    have bounced backwards from her hands on four fear-stiffened legs, but he is not a cat: he is a
    hero. A fundamental disbelief in what he sees before him sustains him, even in the boudoir of
    Countess Nosferatu herself; he would have said, perhaps, <irrational_existence> that there are
        some things which, even if they are true, we should not believe
        possible.</irrational_existence> He might have said: it is folly to believe one's eyes.
        <irrational_existence>Not so much that he does not believe in her; he can see her, she is
        real.</irrational_existence> If she takes off her dark glasses, from her eyes will stream
    all the images that populate this vampire-haunted land, <foredshadowing>but, since he himself is
        immune to shadow, due to his virginity--he does not yet know what there is to be afraid
        of--and due to his heroism, which makes him like the sun, he sees before him, first and
        foremost, an inbred</foredshadowing>, highly strung girl child, fatherless, motherless, kept
    in the dark too long and pale as a plant that never sees the light, half-blinded by some
    hereditary condition of the eyes. And though he feels unease, he cannot feel terror; so he is
    like the boy in the fairy tale, <foreshadowing>who does not know how to shudder</foreshadowing>,
    and not spooks, ghouls, beasties, the Devil himself and all his retinue could do the trick. This
    lack of imagination gives his heroism to the hero. He will learn to shudder in the trenches. But
    this girl cannot make him shudder. Now it is dark. Bats swoop and squeak outside the tightly
    shuttered windows. The coffee is all drunk, the sugar biscuits eaten. Her chatter comes
    trickling and diminishing to a stop; she twists her fingers together, picks at the lace of her
    dress, shifts nervously in her chair. Owls shriek; the impedimenta of her condition squeak and
    gibber all around us. Now you are at the place of annihilation, now you are at the place of
    annihilation. She turns her head away from the blue beams of his eyes s<sexless_temptress>he
        knows no; other consummation than the only one she can offer him</sexless_temptress>. She
    has not eaten for three days. It is dinner-time. It is bedtime. Suivez-moi. Je vous attendais.
    Vous serez ma proie. The raven caws on the accursed roof. 'Dinnertime, dinnertime,' clang the
    portraits on the walls. <sexless_temptress><foreshadowing>A ghastly hunger gnaws her entrails;
            she has waited for him all her life without knowing
        it.</foreshadowing></sexless_temptress> The handsome bicyclist, scarcely believing his luck,
    will follow her into her bedroom; the candles around her sacrificial altar burn with a low,
    clear flame, light catches on the silver tears stitched to the wall. She will assure him, in the
    very voice of temptation: 'My clothes have but to fall and you will see before you a succession
    of mysteries.' <irrational_existence>She has no mouth with which to kiss, no hands with which to
        caress, only the fangs and talons of a beast of prey.</irrational_existence> To touch the
    mineral sheen of the flesh revealed in the cool candle gleam is to invite her fatal embrace; in
    her low, sweet voice, she will croon the lullaby of the House of Nosferatu. Embraces, kisses;
    your golden head, of a lion, although I have never seen a lion, only imagined one, of the sun,
    even if I've only seen the picture of the sun on the Tarot card, <trapped>your golden head of
        the lover whom I dreamed would one day free me</trapped>, this head will fall back, its eyes
    roll upwards <foreshadowing>in a spasm you will mistake for that of love and not of
        death</foreshadowing>. The bridegroom bleeds on my inverted marriage bed. Stark and dead,
    poor bicyclist; he has paid the price of a night with the Countess and some think it too high a
    fee while some do not. Tomorrow, her keeper will bury his bones under her roses. <roses>The food
        her roses feed on gives them their rich colour, their swooning odour, that breathes
        lasciviously of forbidden pleasures.</roses> Suivez-moi. 'Suivez-moi!' The handsome
    bicyclist, fearful for his hostess's health, her sanity, gingerly follows her hysterical
    imperiousness into the other room; he would like to take her into his arms and protect her from
    the ancestors who leer down from the walls. What a macabre bedroom! His colonel, an old goat
    with jaded appetites, had given him the visiting card of a brothel in Paris where, the satyr
    assured him, ten louis would buy just such a lugubrious bedroom, with a naked girl upon a
    coffin; offstage, the brothel pianist played the Dies Irae on a harmonium and, amidst all the
    perfumes of the embalming parlour, the customer took his necrophiliac pleasure of a pretended
    corpse. He had good- naturedly refused the old man's offer of such an initiation; how can he now
    take criminal advantage of the disordered girl with fever-hot, bone-dry, taloned hands and eyes
    that deny all the erotic promises of her body with their terror, their sadness, their dreadful,
    balked tenderness? <trapped>So delicate and damned, poor thing. Quite damned. Yet I do believe
        she scarcely knows what she is doing.</trapped>
    <irrational_existence>She is shaking as if her limbs were not efficiently joined
        together</irrational_existence>, as if she might shake into pieces. She raises her hands to
    unfasten the neck of her dress and her eyes well with tears, they trickle down beneath the rim
    of her dark glasses. She can't take off her mother's wedding dress unless she takes off her dark
    glasses; she has fumbled the ritual, it is no longer inexorable. The mechanism within her fails
    her, now, when she needs it most. When she takes off the dark glasses, they slip from her
    fingers and smash to pieces on the tiled floor. There is no room in her drama for improvisation;
    and this unexpected, mundane noise of breaking glass breaks the wicked spell in the room,
    entirely. She gapes blindly down at the splinters and ineffectively smears the tears across her
    face with her fist. What is she to do now? <spilling_blood>When she kneels to try to gather the
        fragments of glass together, a sharp sliver pierces deeply into the pad of her thumb; she
        cries out, sharp, real.</spilling_blood> She kneels among the broken glass and watches the
    bright bead of blood form a drop. <spilling_blood>She has never seen her own blood before, not
        her own blood. It exercises upon her an awed fascination.</spilling_blood>
    <foreshadowing>Into this vile and murderous room, the handsome bicyclist brings the innocent
        remedies of the nursery; in himself, by his presence, he is an exorcism.</foreshadowing>
    <spilling_blood>He gently takes her hand away from her and dabs the blood with his own
        handkerchief, but still it spurts out. And so he puts his mouth to the wound. He will kiss
        it better for her, as her mother, had she lived, would have done.</spilling_blood> All the
    silver tears fall from the wall with a flimsy tinkle. Her painted ancestors turn away their eyes
    and grind their fangs.<irrational_existence><foreshadowing>How can she bear the pain of becoming
            human? The end of exile is the end of being.</foreshadowing></irrational_existence>
    <foreshadowing>He was awakened by larksong</foreshadowing>. The shutters, the curtains, even the
    long-sealed windows of the horrid bedroom were all opened up and light <foreshadowing>and air
        streamed in; now you could see how tawdry it all was, how thin and cheap the satin, the
        catafalque not ebony at all but black-painted paper stretched on struts of wood, as in the
        theatre.</foreshadowing>
    <roses><spilling_blood>The wind had blown droves of petals from the roses outside into the room
            and this crimson residue swirled fragrantly about the floor</spilling_blood></roses>.
    The candles had burnt out and she must have set her pet lark free because it perched on the edge
    of the silly coffin to sing him its ecstatic morning song. His bones were stiff and aching, he'd
    slept on the floor with his bundled-up jacket for a pillow, after he'd put her to bed.
        <spilling_blood>But now there was no trace of her to be seen, except, lightly tossed across
        the crumpled black satin bedcover, a lace négligé lightly soiled with blood, as it might be
        from a woman's menses, and a rose that must have come from the fierce bushes nodding through
        the window.</spilling_blood> The air was heavy with incense and roses and made him cough.
    The Countess must have got up early to enjoy the sunshine, slipped outside to gather him a rose.
        <foreshadowing>He got to his feet, coaxed the lark on to his wrist and took it to the
        window.</foreshadowing> At first, it exhibited the reluctance for the sky of a long-caged
    thing, but, when <foreshadowing>he tossed it up on to the currents of the air, it spread its
        wings and was up and away into the clear blue bowl of the heavens; he watched its trajectory
        with a lift of joy in his heart.</foreshadowing> Then he padded into the boudoir, his mind
    busy with plans. We shall take her to Zurich, to a clinic; she will be treated for nervous
    hysteria. Then to an eye specialist, for her photophobia, and to a dentist to put her teeth into
    better shape. Any competent manicurist will deal with her claws. <foreshadowing>We shall turn
        her into the lovely girl she is; I shall cure her of all these nightmares.</foreshadowing>
    The heavy curtains are pulled back, to let in brilliant fusillades of early morning light; in
    the desolation of the boudoir, she sits at her round table in her white dress, with the cards
    laid out before her. She has dropped off to sleep over the cards of destiny that are so
    fingered, so soiled, so worn by constant shuffling that you can no longer make the image out on
    any single one of them. She is not sleeping. <beauty_mask>In death, she looked far older, less
        beautiful and so, for the first time, fully human.</beauty_mask>
    <irrational_existence>I will vanish in the morning light; I was only an invention of
        darkness.</irrational_existence>
    <roses>And I leave you as a souvenir the dark, fanged rose I plucked from between my thighs,
        like a flower laid on a grave. On a grave.</roses> My keeper will attend to everything.
    Nosferatu always attends his own obsequies; she will not go to the graveyard unattended. And now
    the crone materialized, weeping, and roughly gestured him to begone. After a search in some
    foul-smelling outhouses, <foreshadowing>he discovered his bicycle and, abandoning his holiday,
        rode directly to Bucharest where, at the poste restante, he found a telegram summoning him
        to rejoin his regiment at once.</foreshadowing><roses>Much later, when he changed back into
        uniform in his quarters, he discovered he still had the Countess's rose</roses>, he must
    have tucked it into the breast pocket of his cycling jacket after he had found her body.
    Curiously enough, although he had brought it so far away from Romania, <roses>the flower did not
        seem to be quite dead and, on impulse, because the girl had been so lovely and her death so
        unexpected and pathetic, he decided to try and resurrect her rose</roses>. He filled his
    tooth glass with water from the carafe on his locker and popped the rose into it, so that its
    withered head floated on the surface. <roses>W<foreshadowing>hen he returned from the mess that
            evening, the heavy fragrance of Count Nosferatu’s roses drifted down the stone corridor
            of the barracks to greet him, and his spartan quarters brimmed with the reeling odour of
            a glowing, velvet, monstrous flower whose petals had regained all their former bloom and
            elasticity, their corrupt, brilliant, baleful splendour.</foreshadowing></roses> Next
    day, his regiment embarked for France.
   
    <!-- element foreshadowing refers to relationship between men (rationality) and women (irrationality), and how they coexist (or don't) -->
</story>
