<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<story>
    <title>Petrosinella</title>
   
    <p>There was once upon a time a <characteristic gender="female">woman</characteristic> named Pascadozzia, who was 
in the family way; and as she was standing one day at a window, which looked 
into the garden of an ogress, she saw a beautiful bed of parsley, for which 
she took such a longing that she was on the point of fainting away; and being
unable to resist her desire, she watched until the ogress went out, and then 
plucked a handful of it. But when the ogress came home, and was going to cook 
her pottage, she found that some one had been at the parsley, and said, 
<quote><villianization cause="revenge">“Ill luck to me but I’ll catch this <characteristic char_type="physical">long-fingered</characteristic> rogue, and make him repent it, 
and teach him to his cost that every one should eat off his own platter, and not
meddle with other folks’ cups.”</villianization></quote></p>

    <p>The <adjective>poor</adjective> <characteristic gender="woman">woman</characteristic> went again and again down into the garden, until one morning the ogress
met her, and in a <characteristic char_type="emotional">furious rage</characteristic> exclaimed, <quote>“Have I caught you at last, you thief, you 
rogue! prithee do you pay the rent of the garden, that you come in this impudent way 
and steal my plants? by my faith, <villianization cause="revenge">but I’ll make you do penance without sending you 
to Rome!”</villianization></quote></p>

    <p>Poor Pascadozzia, in a terrible fright, began to make excuses, saying that neither 
from gluttony nor the craving of hunger had <autonomy auto_type="religious">she been tempted by the devil</autonomy> to commit
this fault, but from her being pregnant, and the fear she had lest the child should 
be born with a crop of parsley on its face; and she added that the ogress ought rather
to thank her, for not having given her sore eyes.</p>

    <p><quote>“Words are but wind,”</quote> answered the ogress; <quote>“I am not to be caught with such
prattle; you have closed the balance-sheet of life,<villianization cause="revenge"> unless you promise to give
me the child you bring forth,</villianization> girl or boy, whichever it may be.”</quote></p>

    <p>Poor Pascadozzia, in order to escape the peril in which she found herself,
swore with one hand upon another to keep the promise: so the ogress let her 
go free. But when her time was come, Pascadozzia gave birth to a <adjective gender="female">little</adjective> girl,
<characteristic char_type="innocent">so beautiful that she was a joy to look upon, who, from having a fine sprig of
parsley on her bosom,</characteristic> was named Petrosinella. And the <adjective gender="female">little</adjective> girl grew from day
to day, until when she was seven years old her mother sent her to school; and 
every time she went along the street and met the ogress, the <characteristic age="old">old</characteristic> woman said to 
her, <quote>“Tell your mother to remember her promise.”</quote> And she went on repeating this 
message so often, that the poor mother, having no longer patience to listen to 
the music, said one day to Petrosinella, <quote>“If you meet the <characteristic age="old">old</characteristic> woman as usual, 
and she reminds you of the hateful promise, answer her, ‘Take it!'”</quote></p>

    <p>When Petrosinella, who dreamt of no ill, met the ogress again, 
and heard her repeat the same words, she answered <characteristic char_type="innocent">innocently</characteristic> as her
mother had told her; where upon the ogress, <autonomy auto_type="controlled">seizing her by her hair</autonomy>, 
carried her off to a wood, which the horses of the Sun never entered, not having 
paid the toll to the pastures of those Shades. Then she put the poor girl into a 
tower, which she caused to arise by her art, and which had neither gate nor 
ladder, but only a little window, through which she ascended and descended by
means of Petrosinella’s hair, which was very long, as the sailor is used to run 
up and down the mast of a ship.</p>

    <p><autonomy auto_type="damsel">Now it happened one day, when the ogress had left the tower, that Petrosinella
put her head out of the little window, and let loose her tresses in the sun;</autonomy> and 
the son of a prince passing by saw those two golden banners, which invited all 
souls to enlist under the standard of Love; and beholding with amazement in the 
midst of those gleaming waves<characteristic depiction="beauty"> a siren’s face, that enchanted all hearts, he fell
desperately in love with such wonderful beauty;</characteristic> and sending her a memorial of sighs, 
she de creed to receive him into favour.</p>

    <p>Matters went on so well with the prince, that there was soon a nodding of heads and
a kissing of hands, a winking of eyes and bowing, thanks and offerings, hopes and promises, 
soft words and compliments. And when this had continued for several days, Petrosinella 
and the prince became so intimate that they made an appointment to meet, and agreed that
it should be at night, when the Moon plays at hide with the Stars; and that Petrosinella 
should give the ogress some poppy-juice, and draw up the prince with her tresses. So when 
the appointed hour came, the prince went to the tower, where Petrosinella, letting fall 
her hair at a given signal, he seized it with both his hands, and cried, <quote>” Draw up!”</quote> And
when he was drawn up, he crept through the little window into the chamber.</p>

    <p>The next morning, before the Sun taught his steeds to leap through the hoop of the Zodiac, 
the prince descended by the same golden ladder, to go his way home. And having repeated these
visits many times, a gossip of the ogress, who was for ever prying into things that did not 
concern her, and poking her nose into every corner, got to find out the secret, and told the 
ogress to be upon the look-out, for that Petrosinella made love with a certain youth, and she 
suspected that matters would go further; adding, that she saw what was going on, and feared 
they would be off and away before May. The ogress thanked her gossip for the information, and
said she would take good care to stop up the road; and as to Petrosinella, <autonomy auto_type="controlled">it was moreover
impossible for her to escape, as she had laid a spell upon her, so that, unless she had in her
hand the three gallnuts which were in a rafter in the kitchen, it would be labour lost to at
tempt to get away.</autonomy></p>

    <p>Whilst they were talking thus together, Petrosinella, who stood with her ears wide open, and 
had some suspicion of the gossip, overheard all that passed. And when Night had spread out her 
black garments to keep them from the moth, and the prince had come as usual, <characteristic char_type="clever">she made him climb
on to the rafters and find the gallnuts, knowing well what effect they would have, as she had 
been enchanted by the ogress.</characteristic></p>
    
    <p>Then, having made a rope-ladder, they both descended to the ground, took to their heels,
and scampered off towards the city. But the gossip happening to see them come out, set up 
a loud halloo, and began to shout and make such a noise that the ogress awoke; and seeing 
that Petrosinella had fled, she descended by the same ladder, which was fastened to the window, 
and set off running after the lovers, who, when they saw her coming at their heels faster than a 
horse let loose, gave themselves up for lost. <characteristic char_type="clever">But Petrosinella, recollecting the gallnuts, quickly
threw one on the ground, and lo! instantly a Corsican bulldog started up,-O mother, such a 
terrible beast!-which with open jaws and barking loud flew at the ogress as if to swallow her at
a mouthful.</characteristic> But the <characteristic age="old">old</characteristic> woman, who was <autonomy auto_type="religious">more cunning and spiteful than the devil</autonomy>, 
<characteristic char_type="clever">put her hand into her pocket, and pulling out a piece of bread, gave it to the dog, which made him hang his 
tail and allay his fury.</characteristic> Then she turned to run after the fugitives again; <characteristic char_type="clever">but Petrosinella,
seeing her approach, threw the second gallnut on the ground, and lo! a fierce lion arose, who, 
lashing the earth with his tail, and shaking his mane, and opening wide his jaws a yard apart,
was just preparing to make a slaughter of the ogress;</characteristic> when, turning quickly back, she stripped the
skin off an ass that was grazing in the middle of a meadow, and ran at the lion, who, fancying it a 
real jackass, was so frightened that he bounded away as fast as he could</p>.
    
<p>The ogress, having leaped over this second ditch, turned again to pursue the poor lovers, who, 
hearing the clatter of her heels and seeing the cloud of dust that rose up to the sky, conjectured 
that she was coming again. But the <characteristic age="old">old</characteristic> woman, who was every moment in dread lest the lion should 
pursue her, had not taken off the ass’s skin; and when <characteristic char_type="clever">Petrosinella now threw down the third gallnut,
there sprang up a wolf, who, without giving the ogress time to play any new trick,</characteristic> gobbled her up 
just as she was, in the shape of a jackass. So the lovers, being now freed from danger, went their 
way leisurely and quietly to the kingdom of the prince, where, with his father’s free consent, he 
took Petrosinella to wife; and thus, after all these storms of fate, they experienced the truth, that
    
<quote>“One hour in port, the sailor freed from fears
 Forgets the tempests of a hundred years.”</quote></p>
</story>