<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<story>
    <title>Rapunzel</title>
    <p> There were once a <characteristic type="male">man</characteristic> and a <characteristic type="woman">woman</characteristic>
wished for a child.  At length the <characteristic type="woman">woman</characteristic> hoped that God
was about to grant her desire.  These people had a little
window at the back of their house from which a splendid garden
could be seen, which was full of the most beautiful flowers and
herbs.  It was, however, surrounded by a high wall, and no one
dared to go into it because it belonged to an <character>enchantress</character>, <autonomy type="evil">who had
great power</autonomy> and was <origin>dreaded by all the world</origin>.  One day the <characteristic type="woman">woman</characteristic>
was standing by this window and looking down into the garden,
when she saw a bed which was planted with the most beautiful
rampion - <character>rapunzel</character>, and it looked so fresh and green that she
longed for it, and had <desire>the greatest desire to eat some.  This desire
increased every day,</desire> and as she knew that she could not get any
of it, she quite pined away, and began to look pale and miserable.
Then her husband was alarmed, and asked, <quote>"what ails you, dear
wife."</quote>  <quote>"Ah, she replied, if I can't eat some of the rampion, which
is in the garden behind our house, I shall die."</quote>  The <characteristic type="man">man</characteristic>, who loved
her, thought, sooner than let your wife die, bring her some of
the rampion yourself, let it cost what it will.  At twilight, he
clambered down over the wall into the garden of the <character>enchantress</character>,
hastily clutched a handful of rampion, and took it to <character>his wife</character>.  She
at once made herself a salad of it, and ate it greedily.  It tasted
so good to her - so very good, that the next day she longed for it
three times as much as before.  If he was to have any rest, her
husband must once more descend into the garden.  In the gloom of
evening, therefore, he let himself down again.  But when he had
clambered down the wall he was terribly afraid, for he saw the
<character>enchantress</character> standing before him.  <quote><autonomy cause="evil">"How can you dare, said she with
angry look, descend into my garden and steal my rampion like a
thief.  You shall suffer for it."</autonomy></quote>  Ah, answered he, "let mercy take
the place of justice, I only made up my mind to do it out of
necessity.  My wife saw your rampion from the window, and felt such
a longing for it that she would have died if she had not got some
to eat." Then the <character>enchantress</character> allowed her anger to be softened, and
said to him,<quote> <villianization cause="revenge">"if the case be as you say, I will allow you to take
away with you as much rampion as you will, only I make one
condition, you must give me the child which your wife will bring
into the world.  It shall be well treated, and I will care for it
like a mother."</villianization></quote>  The <characteristic type="man">man</characteristic> in his terror consented to everything, and
when the <characteristic type="woman">woman</characteristic> was brought to bed, the enchantress appeared at once,
gave the child the name of <character>rapunzel</character>, and took it away with her.
<character>Rapunzel</character> grew into <characteristic value="beauty">the most beautiful child under the sun</characteristic>.
When <characteristic value="young">she was twelve years old</characteristic>, the <character>enchantress</character> <autonomy type="controlled">shut her into a
tower, which lay in a forest, and had neither stairs nor door, but
quite at the top was a little window.</autonomy>  When the <character>enchantress</character>
wanted to go in, she placed herself beneath it and cried,
<quote>"<character>rapunzel</character>, <character>rapunzel</character>,
let down your hair to me."</quote> <character>Rapunzel</character> had 
<characteristic type="physical">magnificent long hair, fine as spun gold,</characteristic> and when
she heard the voice of the <character>enchantress</character> she unfastened <characteristic type="physical">her braided
tresses, wound them round one of the hooks of the window above,
and then the hair fell twenty ells down</characteristic>, and the <character>enchantress</character> climbed
up by it.</p>
<p>After a year or two, it came to pass that the <character>king's son</character> rode
through the forest and passed by the tower. <lovestruck> Then he heard a song,
which was so charming that he stood still and listened.  This was
<character>rapunzel</character>, who in her solitude passed her time in<characteristic value="innocence"> letting her sweet
voice resound.</characteristic>  The <character>king's son</character> wanted to climb up to her, and
looked for the door of the tower, but none was to be found.  He
rode home, but the singing had so deeply touched his heart, that
every day he went out into the forest and listened to it.</lovestruck>  Once when
he was thus standing behind a tree, he saw that an <character>enchantress</character>
came there, and he heard how she cried,
<quote>"<character>rapunzel</character>, <character>rapunzel</character>,
let down your hair."</quote></p>
<p>Then <character>rapunzel</character> let down the braids of her hair, and the
<character>enchantress</character> climbed up to her.  If that is the ladder by which one
mounts, I too will try my fortune, said he, and the next day when
it began to grow dark, he went to the tower and cried,
<quote>"<character>rapunzel</character>, <character>rapunzel</character>,
let down your hair."</quote></p>
Immediately the hair fell down and the <character>king's son</character> climbed up.
<p>At first <character>rapunzel</character> was terribly frightened when a <characteristic type="man">man</characteristic>, such as
her eyes had never yet beheld, came to her.  <lovestruck>But the <character>king's son</character>
began to talk to her quite like a friend, and told her that his
heart had been so stirred that it had let him have no rest, and he
had been forced to see her.  Then <character>rapunzel</character> lost her fear, and when
he asked her if she would take him for her husband, and she saw that
he was young and handsome, she thought, he will love me more than
<characteristic value="old">old</characteristic> <character>dame gothel</character> does.  And she said yes, and laid her hand in his.</lovestruck>
She said, <quote>"I will willingly go away with you, <autonomy type="controlled">but I do not know
how to get down.</autonomy>" </quote> <quote>"Bring with you a skein of silk every time that
you come, and I will weave a ladder with it, and when that is ready
I will descend, and you will take me on your horse."</quote>  They agreed
that until that time he should come to her every evening, for the
old <characteristic type="woman">woman</characteristic> came by day.  The <character>enchantress</character> remarked nothing of
this, until once <character>rapunzel</character> said to her, <quote>"tell me, <character>dame gothel</character>, how
it happens that <characteristic type="physical">you are so much heavier</characteristic> for me to draw up than
the young <character>king's son</character> - he is with me in a moment."</quote>  <quote>"Ah. You
wicked child,"</quote> cried the <character>enchantress</character>.  <quote>"What do I hear you say.  <villianization cause="betrayal">I
thought I had separated you from all the world, and yet you have
deceived me.</villianization>"</quote>  In her anger she clutched <character>rapunzel</character>'s <characteristic type="physical">beautiful
tresses,</characteristic> <autonomy cause="evil">wrapped them twice round her left hand, seized a pair of
scissors with the right, and snip, snap, they were cut off, and the
lovely braids lay on the ground.</autonomy> <autonomy type="damsel"> And she was so pitiless that she
took poor <character>rapunzel</character> into a desert where she had to live in great
grief and misery.</autonomy></p>
<p>On the same day that she cast out <character>rapunzel</character>, <plotting>however, the
<character>enchantress</character> fastened the braids of hair, which she had cut off, to
the hook of the window,</plotting> and when the <character>king's son</character> came and cried,
<quote><character>"rapunzel</character>, <character>rapunzel</character>,
let down your hair,she let the hair down."</quote></p> 
<p>The <character>king's son</character> ascended, but instead of
finding his dearest <character>rapunzel</character>, he found the <character>enchantress</character>, <characteristic type="physical">who gazed
at him with wicked and venomous looks</characteristic>.  <quote>"Aha"</quote>, <autonomy cause="evil">she cried mockingly</autonomy>,
<quote>"you would fetch your dearest, but the <adjective>beautiful</adjective> bird sits
no longer singing in the nest.The cat has got it, and will scratch
out your eyes as well.  <character>Rapunzel</character> is lost to you.  You will never see
her again."</quote>  The <character>king's son</character> <pain>was beside himself with pain, and in
his despair he leapt down from the tower.</pain>  He escaped with his life,
but the thorns into which he fell pierced his eyes.  <sad>Then he
wandered quite blind about the forest, ate nothing but roots and
berries, and did naught but lament and weep over the loss of his
dearest wife.</sad>  Thus he roamed about in misery for some years, and at
length came to the desert where <character>rapunzel</character>, with the twins to which
she had given birth, a boy and a girl, lived in wretchedness.  He
heard a voice, and it seemed so familiar to him that he went towards
it, and when he approached, <character>rapunzel</character> knew him and fell on his neck
and wept.  <magic>Two of her tears wetted his eyes and they grew clear
again, and he could see with them as before.</magic>  He led her to his
kingdom where he was joyfully received, and they lived for a long
time afterwards, happy and contented.</p>
</story>