<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<story>
    <title>Little Red Riding Hood</title>

    <author>Charles Perrault</author>

    <p>Once upon a time there lived in a certain village a <adjective>little country</adjective>
        girl, <characteristic value="beauty">the <adjective>prettiest</adjective> creature who was
            ever seen</characteristic>. <characteristic maternal="loving">Her mother was <adjective>excessively fond</adjective> of her; and her grandmother
        doted on her still more</characteristic>. <menstruation motif="colorred" stereotype="inevitable womanhood">This <adjective>good woman</adjective> had a little red riding hood <autonomy type="submissive">made for her</autonomy>. It
        suited the girl so extremely well that everybody called her Little Red Riding Hood.</menstruation> One day
        her mother, <characteristic value="domesticity">having made some cakes</characteristic>, said to her, <quote><characterstic age="old" value="dependent">Go, my dear, and see how your
            grandmother is doing</characterstic>, for <characteristic age="sick">I hear she has been very ill</characteristic>. Take her a cake, and this little
            pot of butter.</quote></p>

    <p>Little Red Riding Hood set out immediately to go to her grandmother, who <characteristic age="old" value="secluded">lived in another
        village.</characteristic></p>

    <p>As she was going through the wood, <autonomy level="free">she met with a wolf</autonomy>
        <!-- the language here, that she "met with" a wolf almost makes her autonomous, suggesting rather that she did it on her own rather than him approaching her -->, <sex motif="non-consensual">who had a very great mind to eat her
        up, but he dared not, because of some woodcutters working nearby in the forest</sex>. He asked her
        where she was going. <adjective>The poor child</adjective>, <characteristic value="innocence">who did not know that it was dangerous to stay and talk
        to a wolf</characteristic>, said to him, <quote>I am going to see my grandmother and carry her a cake and a
            little pot of butter from my mother.</quote></p>

    <p><quote>Does she live far off?</quote> said the wolf</p>

    <p><quote>Oh I say,</quote> answered Little Red Riding Hood; <quote><characteristic value="ignorant">it is beyond that mill you
            see there, at the first house in the village</characteristic>.</quote></p>

    <p><quote>Well,</quote> said the wolf, <quote>and I'll go and see her too. <autonomy level="free">I'll go this way and
            go you that, and we shall see who will be there first</autonomy>.</quote></p>
    <!-- an interesting difference here, the wolf isn't as explicitly manipulating her. wonder what this could say? -->

    <p>The wolf ran as fast as he could, taking the shortest path, and the little girl took a
        roundabout way, <characteristic stereotype="leisurely" value="beauty">entertaining herself by gathering nuts, running after butterflies, and
        gathering bouquets of little flowers</characteristic>. It was not long before the wolf arrived at the old
        woman's house. He knocked at the door: tap, tap.</p>

    <p>
        <quote>Who's there?</quote>
    </p>

    <p><quote>Your grandchild, Little Red Riding Hood,</quote> replied the wolf, counterfeiting her
        voice; <quote>who has brought you a cake and a little pot of butter sent you by
            mother.</quote></p>

    <p><adjective>The good grandmother</adjective>, <characteristic value="dependent">who was in bed, because she was somewhat ill</characteristic>, cried out, <quote>Pull
            the bobbin, and the latch will go up.</quote></p>

    <p>The wolf pulled the bobbin, and the door opened, and then he immediately fell upon the good
        woman and ate her up in a moment, for it been more than three days since he had eaten. He
        then shut the door and got into the grandmother's bed, expecting Little Red Riding Hood, who
        came some time afterwards and knocked at the door: tap, tap.</p>

    <p>
        <quote>Who's there?</quote>
    </p>

    <p>Little Red Riding Hood, h<characteristic value="trusting">earing the big voice of the wolf, was at first afraid; but believing
        her grandmother had a cold and was hoarse</characteristic>, answered, <quote>It is your grandchild Little Red
            Riding Hood, who has brought you a cake and a little pot of butter mother sends
            you.</quote></p>

    <p>The wolf cried out to her, softening his voice as much as he could, <quote>Pull the bobbin,
            and the latch will go up.</quote></p>

    <p>Little Red Riding Hood pulled the bobbin, and the door opened.</p>

    <p>The wolf, seeing her come in, said to her, hiding himself under the bedclothes, <quote>Put
            the cake and the little pot of butter upon the stool, and <sex>come get into bed with
            me</sex>.</quote></p>

    <p><sex>Little Red Riding Hood took off her clothes and got into bed</sex>. <sex>She was greatly amazed to see
        how her grandmother looked in her nightclothes, and said to her, <quote>Grandmother, what
            big arms you have!</quote></sex></p>
    <!-- literally omg -->

    <quote>All the better to hug you with, my dear.</quote>

    <quote>Grandmother, what big legs you have!</quote>

    <quote>All the better to run with, my child.</quote>

    <quote>Grandmother, what big ears you have!</quote>

    <quote>All the better to hear with, my child.</quote>

    <quote>Grandmother, what big eyes you have!</quote>

    <quote>All the better to see with, my child.</quote>

    <quote>Grandmother, what big teeth you have got!</quote>

    <quote><villainization gender="male" cause="sex">All the better to eat you up with.</villainization></quote>

    <p>And, saying these words, this wicked wolf fell upon Little Red Riding Hood, and ate her all
        up.</p>
<!-- interesting that it ends here and that there is no male savior in this version, warning against sex -->
    <p>Moral: Children, <characteristic value="beauty">especially <adjective>attractive</adjective>, <adjective>well bred young</adjective> ladies</characteristic>, should never talk to
        strangers, for if they should do so, they may well provide dinner for a wolf. <villainization gender="male" cause="sex">I say
            <quote>wolf,</quote> but there are various kinds of wolves.</villainization> There are also those who are
       <adjective> charming, quiet, polite, unassuming, complacent, and sweet,</adjective> who pursue young women at home
        and in the streets. And <villainization gender="male">unfortunately, it is these gentle wolves who are the most dangerous
        ones of all</villainization>.</p>
</story>
