<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../Schemas/grimmprojectschema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<story story_title="rapunzel" version="original">
    <!-- Omg yay! You're associated! -->
    <title>Parsley [Petrosinella]</title>
    <author>Giambattista Basile</author>
    <p>There was once upon a time a woman named Pascadozzia. As she was standing one day at a
        window, which looked into the garden of an ogress, <characteristic depiction="beauty" gender="female">she
            saw a <adjective>beautiful</adjective> bed of parsley, for which she took such a longing
            that she was on the point of fainting away</characteristic>; and being <autonomy auto_type="controlled" gender="female">unable to resist
        her desire</autonomy>,
        she watched until the ogress went out, and then plucked a handful of it.</p>

    <p>But when <characteristic depiction="domesticity" gender="female">the ogress came home, and was going to cook her pottage</characteristic>, she
        found that some one had been at the parsley, and said, <quote>Ill luck to me but I'll catch
            this <adjective>long-fingered</adjective> rogue, <villainization cause="revenge" gender="female">and
                make him repent it, and teach him to his cost that every one should eat off his own
                platter, and not meddle with other folks' cups.</villainization></quote></p>

    <p>The <adjective>poor</adjective> woman went again and again down into the garden, until one
        morning the ogress met her, and in a <characteristic depiction="emotional" gender="female">furious
            rage</characteristic> exclaimed, <quote><characteristic depiction="emotional" gender="female">Have I
                caught you at last, you thief, you rogue? Prithee do you pay the rent of the garden,
                that you come in this impudent way and steal my plants? <autonomy level="evil" gender="female"><villainization cause="revenge">
                    <autonomy level="religious" gender="female">By
                    my faith</autonomy>, but I'll make you do
                    penance!</villainization></autonomy></characteristic></quote></p>

    <p><adjective>Poor</adjective> Pascadozzia, in a terrible fright, began to make excuses, saying
        that neither from gluttony nor the craving of hunger had <autonomy level="religious" gender="female">she
            been tempted by the devil</autonomy> to commit this fault, but fear <characteristic
            depiction="maternal" gender="female">she had lest the child should be born with a crop of parsley on its
            face</characteristic>; and she added that the ogress ought rather to thank her, for not
        having given her sore eyes. <quote>Words are but wind,</quote> answered the ogress; <quote>I
            am not to be caught with such prattle; you have closed the balance sheet of
            life,<villainization cause="revenge" gender="female"><characteristic depiction="maternal" gender="female"> unless you
                    promise to give me the child you bring forth, girl or boy, whichever it may
                    be.</characteristic></villainization></quote></p>

    <p><characteristic depiction="innocent" gender="female"><adjective>Poor</adjective>Pascadozzia</characteristic>, in
        order to escape the peril in which she found herself, swore with one hand upon another to
        keep the promise. So the ogress let her go free. But when her time was come, <reproduction
            rep_type="childbirth">Pascadozzia gave birth to a little girl</reproduction>,
            <characteristic depiction="beauty" gender="female">so beautiful that she was a joy to look
            upon</characteristic>, who, from having a fine sprig of parsley on her bosom, was named
        Parsley. And the <adjective>little</adjective> girl grew from day to day, until when
            <characteristic age="young" gender="female">she was seven years old</characteristic> her mother sent her
        to school; and every time she went along the street and met the ogress, <autonomy level="evil" gender="female"><characteristic
            age="old" gender="female">the old woman</characteristic> said to her, <quote>Tell your mother to
            remember her
            promise.</quote></autonomy></p>

    <p><autonomy level="evil" gender="female">And she went on repeating this message so often</autonomy>, that the
            <adjective>poor</adjective> mother, <autonomy auto_type="controlled" gender="female">having no longer patience to listen to the same
        tale</autonomy>, said one day
        to Parsley, <quote>If you meet the <characteristic age="old" gender="female">old woman</characteristic> as
            usual, and she reminds you of the <adjective>hateful</adjective> promise, answer her,
            'Take it!'</quote>When Parsley,<characteristic depiction="innocent" gender="female">
            who dreamt of no ill,</characteristic> met the ogress again, and heard her repeat the
        same words, <characteristic depiction="naivity" gender="female">she answered
                <adjective>innocently</adjective> as her mother had told her</characteristic>;
        whereupon the ogress, <autonomy auto_type="controlled" gender="female">seizing her by her hair</autonomy>,
            <autonomy auto_type="controlled" gender="female">carried her off to a wood, which the sun never entered.
            Then she put the <adjective>poor</adjective> girl into a tower, <villainization cause="power" gender="female">which she caused to arise by
            her art</villainization>, <characteristic depiction="secluded" gender="female">and which had neither gate nor ladder, but
            only a little window</characteristic>,through which she ascended and descended by means
            of Parsley's hair</autonomy>, which was very long, as the sailor is used to run up and
        down the mast of a ship.</p>

    <p>Now it happened one day, when the ogress had left the tower, <autonomy level="damsel" gender="female">that
            Parsley put her head out of the little window, and let loose her tresses in the
            sun</autonomy>; and the son of <autonomy level="male_savior" gender="male">a prince passing by saw
            these two golden banners, which invited all souls to enlist under the standard of
            love</autonomy>; and beholding with amazement in the midst of those <characteristic
            depiction="beauty" gender="female">gleaming waves a siren's face, that enchanted all hearts, he fell
            <adjective gender="male">desperately</adjective> in love with such
            <adjective gender="female">wonderful</adjective> beauty</characteristic>; and sending her a memorial of
        sighs, she decreed to receive him into favor.</p>

    <p>Matters went on so well with the prince,<characteristic depiction="innocent" gender="female"> that there was soon a nodding of heads and kissing
        of hands, thanks and offerings, hopes and promises, soft words and compliments</characteristic>.
        And when this had continued for several days, Parsley and the prince
        became <reproduction rep_type="sex">so intimate that they made an appointment to meet, and agreed that it should be at
        night</reproduction>, and that <characteristic depiction="clever" gender="female">
        Parsley should give the ogress some poppy juice</characteristic>, and draw up the
        prince with her tresses. So when the appointed hour came, the prince went to the tower,
        where Parsley, letting fall her hair at a given signal, he seized it with both his hands,
        and cried, <quote>Draw up!</quote> And when he was drawn up, <reproduction rep_type="sex">he crept through the little
        window into the chamber.</reproduction></p>

    <p>The next morning early, the prince descended by the same golden ladder, to go his way home.
        And having repeated these visits many times, <villainization cause="power"><autonomy auto_type="controlled" gender="female">a gossip of the ogress, who was for ever prying
        into things that did not concern her</autonomy></villainization>, and
        poking her nose into every corner, got to find out the
        secret, and told the ogress to be upon the lookout, for that Parsley was courted by
            <characteristic age="young" gender="male">a youth</characteristic>.</p>

    <p>The ogress thanked the gossip for the information, and said she would take good care to stop
        up the road; and as to Parsley, <villainization cause="power" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="controlled" gender="female">it was impossible for her
            to escape, as she had laid a spell upon her</autonomy></villainization>, so
        that, unless she had in her hand the three gallnuts which were in a rafter in the kitchen,
       <autonomy auto_type="controlled" gender="female"> it would be labor lost to attempt to get away.</autonomy></p>

    <p>Whilst they were talking thus together, <characteristic depiction="clever" gender="female">Parsley, 
        who stood with her ears wide open, and had
        some suspicion of the gossip, overheard all that passed</characteristic>. And when night had
        spread out her black garments, and the prince had come as usual, <characteristic
        depiction="clever" gender="female">she made him climb onto the rafters and find the gallnuts, knowing
        well what effect they would have, as she had been enchanted by the
        ogress</characteristic>. Then, having made a rope ladder, <autonomy auto_type="free" gender="female">
        they both descended to the ground, took to their heels, and scampered off towards the
        city</autonomy>.</p>

    <p>But the gossip happening to see them come out, set up a loud halloo, and began to shout and
        make such a noise that the ogress awoke; and seeing that Parsley had fled, she descended by
        the same ladder, which was fastened to the window, and set off running after the
        lovers, who, when they saw her coming at their heels faster than a horse
        let loose, gave themselves up for lost. <autonomy level="heroine" gender="female">But Parsley, recollecting
            the gallnuts, quickly threw one on the ground</autonomy>, and lo! instantly a Corsican
        bulldog started up, -- a terrible beast! -- which with open jaws and barking loud flew at
        the ogress as if to swallow her at a
        mouthful. <villainization cause="power" gender="female">
            But the <characteristic age="old" gender="female"
            >old woman</characteristic>, who was <autonomy level="religious" gender="female">more
                <adjective>cunning</adjective> and <adjective>spiteful</adjective> than the
            devil</autonomy>,</villainization>
        <characteristic depiction="clever" gender="female"><characteristic depiction="brave" gender="female">
            put her hand into her pocket, and pulling out a piece of
            bread, gave it to the dog,</characteristic> which made him hang his tail and allay his
            fury.</characteristic></p>

    <p>Then she turned to run after the fugitives again; <autonomy level="heroine" gender="female">but Parsley,
            <characteristic depiction="brave" gender="female">seeing her approach, threw the second gallnut on
                the ground</characteristic></autonomy>,
        and lo! a fierce lion arose, who, lashing the earth with his tail, <villainization cause="power">and shaking his mane, and
        opening wide his jaws a yard apart, was just preparing to make a slaughter of the
        ogress</villainization>; <characteristic
            depiction="clever" gender="female">when, turning quickly back,<characteristic depiction="clever" gender="female"> 
                she stripped the skin off an ass that was
            grazing in the middle of a meadow, and ran at the lion</characteristic></characteristic>, who, fancying
        it a real jackass, was so frightened that he bounded away as fast
        as he could.</p>

    <p>The ogress, having leaped over this second ditch, turned again to pursue the
            <adjective>poor</adjective> lovers, who, hearing the clatter of her heels and seeing
        the cloud of dust that rose up to the sky, conjectured that she was coming again. But the
            <characteristic age="old" gender="female">old woman</characteristic>, who was every moment in dread lest
        the lion should pursue her, had not taken off the ass's skin; <autonomy level="heroine" gender="female">and
            when Parsley now threw down the third gallnut</autonomy>, there sprang up a wolf, who,
        without giving the ogress time to play any new trick, gobbled her up just as she was, in the
        shape of a jackass.</p>

    <p><autonomy auto_type="free" gender="female">So the lovers, being now freed from danger</autonomy>,
        <characteristic depiction="innocent" gender="female"> went their
        way <adjective>leisurely</adjective> and <adjective>quietly</adjective></characteristic> to the kingdom of the
        prince, where, with his
        father's <adjective>free</adjective> consent, he took Parsley to wife; and thus, after all these storms of fate,
        they experienced the truth, that One hour in port, the sailor freed from fears Forgets the
        tempests of a hundred years. Zeza's story was listened to with such delight to the end,
        that, had it even continued for an hour longer, the time would have appeared only a
        moment.</p>
</story>
