
<?xml-model href="folklore/Schemas/grimmprojectschema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<story><title>The Sleeping Beauty in the Wood</title>
    <author>Charles Perrault</author> 
    
    <p>Once upon a time there <characteristic depiction="maternal" char_type="nonphysical" gender="female">lived a king and queen who were grieved, more grieved than words can
        tell, because they had no children</characteristic>. They tried the waters of every country, made vows and
        pilgrimages, and did everything that could be done, but without result. At last, however,
        <characteristic depiction="maternal" char_type="nonphysical" gender="female">the queen found that her wishes were fulfilled, and in due course she gave birth to a
        daughter.</characteristic></p>
    
    
    <p>A grand christening was held, and all the fairies that could be found in the realm (they
        numbered seven in all) were <characteristic char_type="nonphysical" depiction="maternal" age="old" gender="female">invited to be godmothers to the little princess</characteristic>. This was done
        so that by means of the gifts which each in turn would bestow upon her (in accordance with
        the fairy custom of those days) <characteristic depiction="innocent" gender="female">the princess might be endowed with every imaginable
        perfection</characteristic>.</p>
    
    
    <p>When the christening ceremony was over, all the company returned to the <adjective gender="male">king's palace</adjective>, where
        a great banquet was held in honor of the fairies. Places were laid for them in magnificent
        style, and before each was placed a solid gold casket containing a spoon, fork, and knife of
        fine gold, set with diamonds and rubies. <villainization cause="jealousy" gender="female">But just as all were sitting down to table an aged
        fairy was seen to enter, whom no one had thought to invite</villainization> -- the reason being that for more
        than fifty years she had never quitted the tower in which she lived, and <villainization cause="unspecified" gender="female">people had supposed
        her to be dead or bewitched</villainization>.</p>
    
    
    <p>By the king's orders a place was laid for her, but it was impossible to give her a golden
        casket like the others, for only seven had been made for the seven fairies. <villainization cause="jealousy" gender="female">The <adjective gender="female">old creature</adjective>
        believed that she was intentionally slighted, and muttered threats between her teeth.</villainization></p>
    
    
    <p>She was overheard by one of the <adjective gender="female">young fairies</adjective>, who was seated nearby. The latter, guessing
        that some mischievous gift might be bestowed upon the little princess, hid behind the
        tapestry as soon as the company left the table. <villainization cause="unspecified" gender="female">Her intention was to be the last to speak,
        and so to have the power of counteracting, as far as possible, any evil which the <adjective gender="female">old</adjective> fairy
        might do.</villainization></p>
    
    
    <p> Presently the fairies began to bestow their gifts upon the princess. The <adjective gender="female">youngest ordained </adjective>
        that she should be the <characteristic depiction="beauty" char_type="physical" gender="female">most <adjective gender="female">beautiful</adjective> person in the world</characteristic>; the next, that she should have
        <characteristic depiction="innocent" char_type="nonphysical" gender="female"> the temper of an angel</characteristic>; the third, that she should <characteristic depiction="innocent" char_type="nonphysical" gender="female">do everything with wonderful grace</characteristic>; the
        fourth, that <characteristic depiction="beauty" char_type="physical">she should dance to perfection</characteristic>; the fifth, <characteristic depiction="beauty" char_type="physical" gender="female">that she should sing like a
        nightingale</characteristic>; and the sixth, that she should play every kind of music with the utmost skill.</p>
    
    
    <p><autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">It was now the turn of the <adjective gender="female">aged</adjective> fairy. Shaking her head, <villainization cause="revenge" gender="female">in token of spite rather than of
        infirmity,</villainization> she declared that the princess should <reproduction rep_type="menstruation">prick her hand with a spindle</reproduction>, and die of
        it. A shudder ran through the company at this <adjective gender="female">terrible</adjective> gift. All eyes were filled with
        tears.</autonomy></p>
    
    
    <p>But at this moment the young fairy stepped forth from behind the tapestry.</p>
    
    
    <p><quote>Take comfort, your Majesties,</quote> she cried in a loud voice. <quote>Your
            daughter shall not die. <villainization cause="unspecified" gender="female">My power, it is true, is not enough to undo all that my aged
            kinswoman has decreed.</villainization> The princess will indeed <reproduction rep_type="menstruation">prick her hand with a spindle</reproduction>. But
            instead of dying she shall merely fall into a profound slumber that will last a hundred
            years. <autonomy auto_type="controlled" level="damsel" gender="female">At the end of that time a king's son shall come to awaken her.</autonomy></quote></p>
    
    
    <p>The king, in an attempt to <autonomy auto_type="free" level="male_savior" gender="male">avert</autonomy> the unhappy doom pronounced by the old fairy, at once
        published an edict forbidding all persons, under pain of death, to use a spinning wheel or
        keep a spindle in the house.</p>
    
    
    <p><characteristic char_type="nonphysical" gender="female" depiction="naivity" age="young">At the end of fifteen or sixteen years the king and queen happened one day to be away, on
        pleasure bent. The princess was running about the castle, and going upstairs from room to
        room she came at length to a garret at the top of a tower, where an old serving woman sat
        alone with her distaff, spinning. This good woman had never heard speak of the king's
        proclamation forbidding the use of spinning wheels</characteristic>.</p>
    
    
    <p><quote>What are you doing, my good woman?</quote> asked the princess. </p>
    
    
    <p><quote>I am spinning, my <adjective gender="female">pretty</adjective> child,</quote> replied the dame, <characteristic depiction="naivity" char_type="nonphysical" age="old" gender="female">not knowing who she
        was.</characteristic></p>
    
    
    <p><quote><characteristic depiction="naivity" char_type="nonphysical" age="young" gender="female">"Oh, what fun!"</characteristic></quote> rejoined the princess. <quote>How do you do it? Let me try
            and see if I can do it equally well.</quote></p>
    
    
    <p> <autonomy auto_type="free" level="damsel" gender="female">Partly because she was too <adjective gender="female">hasty</adjective>, partly because she was a little <adjective gender="female">heedless</adjective>, but also because
        the fairy decree had ordained it, no sooner had she seized the spindle than she <reproduction rep_type="menstruation">pricked her
        hand and fell down in a swoon.</reproduction></autonomy></p> 
    
   <p> In great alarm the <adjective gender="female">good</adjective> dame cried out for help. People
    came running from every quarter to the princess. They threw water on her face, chafed her with
    their hands, and rubbed her temples with the royal essence of Hungary. But nothing would restore
    her.</p>
    
    <p> <autonomy auto_type="free" level="male_savior" gender="male">Then the king, who had been brought upstairs by the commotion, remembered the fairy
        prophecy.</autonomy> Feeling certain that what had happened was inevitable, since the fairies had
        decreed it, he gave orders that the princess should be placed in the finest apartment in the
        palace, <characteristic depiction="beauty" char_type="physical" gender="female">upon a bed embroidered in gold and silver.</characteristic></p>
    
    
    <p><characteristic depiction="beauty" char_type="physical" age="young" gender="female">You would have thought her an <adjective gender="female">angel</adjective>, so fair was she to behold. The trance had not taken away
        the <adjective gender="female">lovely color</adjective> of her complexion. Her cheeks were <adjective gender="female">delicately</adjective> flushed, her lips like coral.</characteristic>
        Her eyes, indeed, were closed, but her <adjective gender="female">gentle</adjective> breathing could be heard, and it was therefore
        plain that she was not dead. <autonomy auto_type="free" level="male_savior" gender="male">The king commanded</autonomy> that she should be left to sleep in peace
        <autonomy auto_type="controlled" level="damsel" gender="female">until the hour of her awakening should come.</autonomy></p>
    
    
    <p> When the accident happened to the princess, the <adjective gender="female">good</adjective> fairy who had saved her life by
        condemning her to sleep a hundred years was in the kingdom of Mataquin, twelve thousand
        leagues away. She was instantly warned of it, however, by a little dwarf who had a pair of
        seven-league boots, which are boots that enable one to cover seven leagues at a single step.
        The fairy set off at once, and within an hour her chariot of fire, drawn by dragons, was
        seen approaching. </p>
    
    
    <p>The king handed her down from her chariot, and she approved of all that he had done. But
        being gifted with great powers of foresight, she bethought herself that when the princess
        came to be awakened, <characteristic depiction="emotional" age="young" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="controlled" level="damsel" gender="female">she would be much distressed to find herself all alone in the old
        castle.</autonomy></characteristic> And this is what she did.</p>
    
    
    <p><autonomy auto_type="free" level="heroine" gender="female">She touched with her wand everybody</autonomy> (except the king and queen) who was in the castle --
        governesses, maids of honor, ladies-in-waiting, gentlemen, officers, stewards, cooks,
        scullions, errand boys, guards, porters, pages, footmen. She touched likewise all the horses
        in the stables, with their grooms, the big mastiffs in the courtyard, and little Puff, the
        pet dog of the princess, who was lying on the bed beside his mistress. The moment she had
        touched them they all fell asleep, to awaken only at the same moment as their mistress. <autonomy auto_type="controlled" level="damsel" gender="female">Thus
        they would always be ready with their service whenever she should require it.</autonomy> The very spits
        before the fire, loaded with partridges and pheasants, subsided into slumber, and the fire
        as well. All was done in a moment, for the fairies do not take long over their work.</p>
    
    
    <p>Then the king and queen kissed their <adjective gender="female">dear</adjective> child, without waking her, and left the castle.
        Proclamations were issued, forbidding any approach to it, but these warnings were not
        needed, for within a quarter of an hour there grew up all round the park so vast a quantity
        of trees big and small,<autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female"> with interlacing brambles and thorns, that neither man nor beast
        could penetrate them.</autonomy> The tops alone of the castle towers could be seen, and these only from
        a distance. Thus did the fairy's magic contrive that the princess, during all the time of
        her slumber, should have naught whatever to fear from prying eyes.</p>
    
    
    <p>At the end of a hundred years the throne had passed to another family from that of the
        sleeping princess. One day the king's son chanced to go a-hunting that way, and seeing in
        the distance some towers in the midst of a large and dense forest, he asked what they were.
        His attendants told him in reply the various stories which they had heard. Some said there
        was an old castle haunted by ghosts, others that all the witches of the neighborhood held
        their revels there. The favorite tale was that in the castle lived an ogre, who carried
        thither all the children whom he could catch. There he devoured them at his leisure, and
        since he was the only person who could force a passage through the wood nobody had been able
        to pursue him.</p>
    
    
    <p> While the prince was wondering what to believe, an old peasant took up the tale. </p>
    
    
    <p><quote>Your Highness,</quote> said he, <quote>more than fifty years ago I heard my father
            say that in this castle lies a princess, <characteristic depiction="beauty" char_type="physical" age="young" gender="female">the <adjective gender="female">most beautiful</adjective> that has ever been seen.</characteristic> It
        is her doom to sleep there for a hundred years, and <autonomy auto_type="free" level="male_savior" gender="male">then to be awakened by a king's son,
            for whose coming she waits.</autonomy></quote></p>
    
    
    <p> <autonomy auto_type="free" level="male_savior" gender="male">This story <adjective gender="male">fired</adjective> the young prince. He jumped immediately to the conclusion that it was for
        him to see so gay an adventure through, and <adjective gender="male">impelled</adjective> alike by the wish for love and glory,
        he <adjective gender="male">resolved</adjective> to set about it on the spot. </autonomy></p>
    
    
    <p> Hardly had he taken a step towards the wood when the tall trees, <autonomy auto_type="free" level="male_savior" gender="male">the brambles and the
        thorns, separated of themselves and made a path for him</autonomy>. He turned in the direction of the
        castle, and espied it at the end of a long avenue. This avenue he entered, and was surprised
        to notice that the trees closed up again as soon as he had passed, so that none of his
        retinue were able to follow him. <autonomy auto_type="free" level="male_savior" gender="male">A young and <adjective gender="male">gallant</adjective> prince is always <adjective gender="male">brave</adjective>,</autonomy> however; so he
        continued on his way, and presently reached a large forecourt.</p>
    
    
    <p>The sight that now met his gaze was enough to fill him with an icy fear. The silence of the
        place was dreadful, and death seemed all about him. The recumbent figures of men and animals
        had all the appearance of being lifeless, until he perceived by the pimply noses and ruddy
        faces of the porters, that they merely slept. It was plain, too, from their glasses, in
        which were still some dregs of wine, that they had fallen asleep while drinking.</p>
    
    
    <p>The prince made his way into a great courtyard, paved with marble, and mounting the staircase
        entered the guardroom. Here the guards were lined up on either side in two ranks, their
        muskets on their shoulders, snoring their hardest. Through several apartments crowded with
        ladies and gentlemen in waiting, some seated, some standing, but all asleep, he pushed on,
        and so came at last to a chamber which was decked all over with gold. <characteristic depiction="beauty" char_type="physical" age="young" gender="female">There he encountered
        the most beautiful sight he had ever seen.</characteristic> Reclining upon a bed, the curtains of which on
        every side were drawn back, was <characteristic depiction="beauty" char_type="physical" age="young" gender="female">a princess of seemingly some fifteen or sixteen summers,
        whose <adjective gender="female">radiant beauty</adjective> had an almost <adjective gender="female">unearthly</adjective> luster.</characteristic></p>
    
    
    <p><characteristic depiction="beauty" char_type="physical" age="young" gender="female">Trembling in his admiration he drew near and went on his knees beside her.</characteristic> At the same
        moment, <autonomy auto_type="controlled" level="damsel" gender="female">the hour of disenchantment having come, the princess awoke, and bestowed upon him a
        look more <adjective gender="female">tender</adjective> than a first glance might seem to warrant.</autonomy></p>
    
    
    <p><quote>Is it you, dear prince?</quote> she said. <quote><autonomy auto_type="controlled" level="damsel" gender="female">You have been long in
            coming!</autonomy></quote></p>
    
    
    <p><characteristic depiction="innocent" age="young" gender="female">Charmed by these words, and especially by the manner in which they were said, the prince
        scarcely knew how to express his delight and gratification.</characteristic> <autonomy auto_type="free" level="male_savior" gender="male">He declared that he loved her
        better than he loved himself.</autonomy> His words were faltering, but they pleased the more for that.
        The less there is of eloquence, the more there is of love.</p>
    
    
    <p>Her embarrassment was less than his, and that is not to be wondered at, since she had had
        time to think of what she would say to him. It seems (although the story says nothing about
        it) <characteristic depiction="naivity" age="young" gender="female">that the good fairy had beguiled her long slumber with <adjective gender="female">pleasant</adjective> dreams.</characteristic> To be brief,
        <characteristic depiction="innocent" age="young" gender="female">after four hours of talking they had not succeeded in uttering one half of the things they
        had to say to each other.</characteristic></p>
    
    
    <p> Now the whole palace had awakened with the princess. Everyone went about his business, and
        since they were not all in love they presently began to feel mortally hungry. The
        lady-in-waiting, who was suffering like the rest, at length lost patience, and in a loud
        voice called out to the princess that supper was served. </p>
    
    
    <p>The princess was already fully dressed, <characteristic depiction="beauty" char_type="physical" age="young" gender="female">and in most <adjective gender="female">magnificent</adjective> style</characteristic>. <autonomy auto_type="controlled" level="damsel" gender="female">As he helped her to
        rise,</autonomy> the prince refrained from telling her that her clothes, with the straight collar which
        she wore, were like those to which his grandmother had been accustomed. <characteristic depiction="beauty" char_type="physical" age="young" gender="female">And in truth, they
        in no way detracted from her beauty.</characteristic></p>
    
    
    <p>They passed into an apartment hung with mirrors, and were there served with supper by the
        stewards of the household, while the fiddles and oboes played some old music and played it
        remarkably well, considering they had not played at all for just upon a hundred years. A
        little later, when supper was over, <autonomy auto_type="controlled" level="societal_expectations" gender="female">the chaplain married them in the castle chapel</autonomy>, and in
        due course, attended by the courtiers in waiting, they retired to rest.</p>
    
    
    <p> They slept but little, however. The princess, indeed, had not much need of sleep, and as
        <autonomy auto_type="free" level="male_savior" gender="male">soon as morning came the prince took his leave of her.</autonomy> He returned to the city, and told his
        father, who was awaiting him with some anxiety, that he had lost himself while hunting in
        the forest, but had obtained some black bread and cheese from a charcoal burner, in whose
        hovel he had passed the night.</p>
    
    
    <p> His royal father, being of an easygoing nature, believed the tale, <autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">but his mother was not so
        easily hoodwinked.</autonomy> She noticed that he now went hunting every day, and that he always had an
        excuse handy when he had slept two or three nights from home. She felt certain, therefore,
        that he had some love affair.</p>
    
    
    <p><characteristic depiction="maternal" gender="female">Two whole years passed since the marriage of the prince and princess, and during that time
        they had two children.</characteristic> The first, a daughter, was called Dawn, while the second, a boy,
        was named Day, <characteristic depiction="beauty" char_type="physical" age="young" gender="male">because he seemed even more beautiful than his sister.</characteristic></p>
    
    
    <p> Many a time the queen told her son that he ought to settle down in life. <autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">She tried in this
        way to make him confide in her</autonomy>, but he did not dare to trust her with his secret. Despite
        the affection which he bore her, <villainization cause="jealousy" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">he was afraid of his mother, for she came of a <adjective gender="female">race of
        ogres,</adjective></autonomy></villainization> <characteristic depiction="innocent" char_type="nonphysical" age="old" gender="female">and the king had only married her for her wealth.</characteristic></p>
    
    
    <p>It was whispered at the court that she had <villainization cause="unspecified" gender="female"><adjective gender="female">ogreish instincts</adjective></villainization>, <villainization cause="jealousy" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">and that when little children
        were near her she had the greatest difficulty in the world to keep herself from <adjective gender="female">pouncing</adjective> on
        them.</autonomy></villainization></p>
    
    
    <p> No wonder the prince was reluctant to say a word.</p>
    
    
    <p>But at the end of two years the king died, and the prince found himself on the throne. He
        then made public announcement of his marriage, and went in state to fetch his royal consort
        from her castle. With her two children beside her she made a <adjective gender="female">triumphal entry</adjective> into the
        capital of her husband's realm.</p>
    
    
    <p>Some time afterwards the king declared war on his neighbor, the Emperor Cantalabutte. He
        appointed the queen mother as regent in his absence, <characteristic depiction="maternal" age="old" gender="female">and entrusted his wife and children to
        her care.</characteristic></p>
    
    
    <p>He expected to be away at the war for the whole of the summer, and as soon as he was gone the
        queen mother sent her daughter-in-law and the two children to a country mansion in the
        forest. This she did that she might be able the more easily to gratify her <adjective gender="female">horrible
        longings</adjective>. A few days later she went there and in the evening summoned the chief steward.</p>
    
    
    <p><quote>For my dinner tomorrow,</quote> she told him, <quote><villainization cause="jealousy" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">I will eat little
            Dawn.</autonomy></villainization></quote></p>
    
    
    <p><quote>Oh, Madam!</quote> exclaimed the steward. </p>
    
    
    <p><quote>That is my will,</quote> said the queen; and <villainization cause="jealousy" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">she spoke in the <adjective gender="female">tones of an ogre</adjective> who
        longs for raw meat.</autonomy></villainization></p>
    
    
    <p><quote>You will serve her with piquant sauce,</quote> she added.</p>
    
    
    <p>The <adjective gender="male">poor</adjective> man, seeing plainly that it was <autonomy auto_type="controlled" level="evil" gender="male">useless to trifle with an ogress</autonomy>, took his big knife
        and went up to <adjective gender="female">little</adjective> Dawn's chamber. She was at that time four years old, and when she came
        running <characteristic depiction="innocent" age="young" gender="female">with a smile to greet him, flinging her arms round his neck and <adjective gender="female">coaxing</adjective> him to give
        her some sweets</characteristic>, he burst into tears, and let the knife fall from his hand.</p>
    
    
    <p> Presently he went down to the yard behind the house, and slaughtered a young lamb. For this
        he made so delicious a sauce that his mistress declared she had never eaten anything so
        good.</p>
    
    
    <p>At the same time the steward carried <adjective gender="female">little</adjective> Dawn to his wife, and bade the latter
    hide her in the quarters which they had below the yard.</p>
    
    
   <p> Eight days later <villainization cause="jealousy" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">the <adjective gender="female">wicked</adjective> queen</autonomy></villainization> summoned her steward again.</p> 
    
    
    <p><quote>For my supper,</quote> she announced, <quote><villainization cause="jealousy" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">I will eat <adjective gender="male">little</adjective> Day.</autonomy></villainization></quote></p> 
    
    
   <p> The steward made no answer, being determined to trick her as he had done previously. He went in search of
    little Day, whom he found with a tiny foil in his hand, making <adjective gender="male">brave</adjective> passes -- though he was but
    three years old -- at a big monkey. <characteristic depiction="maternal" age="old" gender="female">He carried him off to his wife, who stowed him away in
    hiding with little Dawn.</characteristic> To the ogress the steward served up, in place of Day, a young kid so
    tender that she found it surpassingly delicious.</p>
    
    
    <p>So far, so good. But there came an evening when <villainization cause="jealousy" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">this <adjective gender="female">evil</adjective> queen</autonomy></villainization> again addressed the steward.</p>
    
    
   <p><quote>I have a mind,</quote> she said, <quote><villainization cause="jealousy" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">to eat the queen with the same sauce as you served with her children.</autonomy></villainization></quote></p> 
    
    
   <p>This time the poor steward despaired of being able to practice another deception. The <adjective gender="female">young</adjective> queen was twenty years old, without counting the
    hundred years she had been asleep. <characteristic depiction="beauty" char_type="physical" age="young" gender="female">Her skin, though <adjective gender="female">white and beautiful</adjective>, had become a little
    <adjective gender="female">tough</adjective>,</characteristic> and what animal could he possibly find that would correspond to her? He made up his mind
    that if <autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="male">he would save his own life he must kill the queen</autonomy>, and went upstairs to her apartment
    determined to do the deed once and for all. Goading himself into a rage he drew his knife and
    entered the <adjective gender="female">young</adjective> queen's chamber, but a reluctance to give her no moment of grace made him
    repeat <adjective gender="male">respectfully</adjective> the command which he had received from the queen mother.</p> 
    
    
    <p><quote>Do it! do it!</quote> she cried, baring her neck to him; <quote><characteristic depiction="maternal" gender="female">carry out the order you have been given! Then once more I shall
    see my children, my poor children that I loved so much!</characteristic></quote></p>
    
    
    <p>Nothing had been said to her when the children were stolen away, and she believed them to be dead.</p>
    
    
   <p> The poor steward was <adjective gender="male">overcome by compassion</adjective>. <quote>No, no, Madam,</quote> he declared.<quote>You shall not die, <characteristic depiction="maternal" gender="female">but you shall certainly see your
    children again.</characteristic> That will be in my quarters, where I have hidden them. I shall make the queen
    eat a young hind in place of you, and thus trick her once more.</quote></p> 
    
    
    <p>Without more ado he led her to his quarters, and leaving her there to <characteristic depiction="maternal" gender="female">embrace and weep over her children</characteristic>, proceeded to cook a
    hind with such art that the queen mother ate it for her supper with as much appetite as if it
    had indeed been the <adjective gender="female">young</adjective> queen.</p> 
    
    
    <p> <villainization cause="unspecified" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">The queen mother felt well satisfied with her <adjective gender="female">cruel</adjective>deeds</autonomy></villainization>, and
        planned to tell the king, on his return, <villainization cause="unspecified" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">that savage wolves had devoured his consort and his
    children. It was her habit, however, to <adjective gender="female">prowl</adjective> often about the courts and alleys of the mansion,
    in the hope of scenting raw meat,</autonomy></villainization> and one evening she heard the little boy Day crying in a
    basement cellar. <characteristic depiction="maternal" gender="female">The child was weeping because his mother had threatened to whip him for some
    naughtiness,</characteristic> and she heard at the same time <characteristic depiction="innocent" age="young" gender="female">the voice of Dawn begging forgiveness for her
    brother.</characteristic></p> 
    
    
    <p><villainization cause="unspecified" gender="female">The ogress recognized the voices of the queen and her children, <autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">and was enraged to find
    she had been tricked.</autonomy></villainization> The next morning, in tones so affrighting that all trembled, she ordered a
        huge vat to be brought into the middle of the courtyard. <villainization cause="jealousy" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">This she filled with vipers and toads,
    with snakes and serpents of every kind, intending to cast into it the queen and her children,</autonomy></villainization>
    and the steward with his wife and serving girl. By her command these were brought forward, with
    their hands tied behind their backs.</p> 
    
    
    <p> There they were, and <villainization cause="jealousy" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">her <adjective gender="female">minions</adjective> were making ready to cast
    them into the vat,</autonomy></villainization>when into the courtyard <autonomy auto_type="free" level="male_savior" gender="male">rode the king! Nobody had expected him so soon, but
    he had traveled posthaste. Filled with amazement, he demanded to know what this <adjective gender="female">horrible
    spectacle</adjective> meant.</autonomy></p> 
    
    
    <p>None dared tell him, and at that moment <villainization cause="jealousy" gender="female"><autonomy auto_type="free" level="evil" gender="female">the ogress, enraged at what confronted
    her, threw herself head foremost into the vat, and was devoured on the instant by the <adjective gender="female">hideous</adjective>
    creatures she had placed in it.</autonomy></villainization></p> 
    
    
    <p>The king could not but be sorry, for after all she was his
    mother; but it was not long before he found ample consolation in <characteristic depiction="beauty" char_type="physical" gender="female">his beautiful wife and
    children.</characteristic></p> 

<!--The ogre queen can also be seen as a wicked (evil) stepmother figure (despite her not being an actual stepmother), her evil actions driven by jealousy over the young, beautiful new family (her son's family)-->
        
</story>
