<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../Schemas/grimmprojectschema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>

<!--Cannot get the error messages off of the quote tags-->
<story>
    
    <title>Little Snow-white</title> 
    
    <p>Once upon a time in the middle of winter, when the flakes of
        snow were falling like feathers from the sky, a queen sat at a window sewing, and the frame of
        the window was made of black ebony. And whilst she was sewing and looking out of the window at
        the snow, <reproduction rep_type="childbirth">she pricked her finger with the needle, and three drops of blood fell upon the snow.</reproduction>
        And the red looked pretty upon the white snow, and she thought to herself, <quote>Would that I had a
            <characteristic char_type="physical">child as <adjective gender="female">white as snow</adjective>, as <reproduction rep_type="menstruation">red as blood</reproduction>, and as black as the wood of the window-frame</characteristic>.</quote></p>
    
    <p>Soon after that she had a<characteristic char_type="physical"><adjective gender="female">little</adjective> daughter, who was as <adjective gender="female">white as snow</adjective>, and as <reproduction rep_type="menstruation">red as blood</reproduction>, and her
        hair was as black as ebony;</characteristic>and she was therefore called <adjective gender="female">Little</adjective> Snow-white. And when the child
        was born, the Queen died.</p> 
    
    <p>After a year had passed the King took to himself another wife. She was<characteristic depiction="beauty">
        a beautiful woman, but <adjective gender="female">proud and haughty</adjective>, and she could not bear that anyone else should surpass
        her in beauty.</characteristic> She had a wonderful looking-glass, and when she stood in front of it and looked
        at herself in it, and said—<villainization cause="competition">
            <quote>Looking-glass, Looking-glass, on the wall, Who in this land is the
                <adjective gender="female">fairest</adjective> of all?</quote>
            the looking-glass answered— 
            <quote>Thou, O Queen, art the fairest of all!</quote></villainization>
        Then she was satisfied, for she knew that the looking-glass spoke the truth.</p> 
    
    <p><characteristic depiction="beauty">But Snow-white was growing
        up, and grew more and more beautiful; and when she was seven years old she was as beautiful as
        the day, and <adjective gender="female">more beautiful than the Queen herself</adjective>.</characteristic>And once when the Queen asked her
        looking-glass—<villainization cause="competition">
            <quote>Looking-glass, Looking-glass, on the wall, Who in this land is the fairest of
                all? </quote>
            it answered— 
            <quote>Thou art fairer than all who are here, Lady Queen.” <characteristic depiction="beauty">But more beautiful still
                is Snow-white,</characteristic> as I ween.</quote>
            Then the Queen was shocked, and turned yellow and green with envy.
            From that hour, whenever she looked at Snow-white, her heart heaved in her breast, she <adjective gender="female">hated</adjective> the
            girl so much.</villainization></p> 
    
    <p><villainization cause="jealousy">And <adjective gender="female">envy and pride</adjective> grew higher and higher in her heart like a weed, so that she
        had no peace day or night. She called a huntsman, and said, <autonomy level="evil"><quote>Take the child away into the
            forest; I will no longer have her in my sight. Kill her, and bring me back her heart as a
            token.</quote></autonomy></villainization> <autonomy level="evil">The huntsman obeyed, and took her away;</autonomy> but when he had drawn his knife, and was about
        to pierce <characteristic depiction="innocent">Snow-white’s <adjective gender="female">innocent</adjective> heart,</characteristic> she began to weep, and said, <quote><autonomy auto_type="free" gender="female" level="damsel">Ah dear huntsman, leave me
            my life! I will run away into the wild forest, and never come home again.</autonomy></quote></p>
    
    <p><characteristic depiction="beauty">And as she was so
        beautiful</characteristic> the huntsman had <adjective gender="male">pity</adjective> on her and said, <quote>Run away, then, you <adjective gender="female">poor child</adjective>.</quote> <quote><autonomy auto_type="free" gender="female" level="damsel">The wild
            beasts will soon have devoured you,</autonomy></quote> thought he, and yet it seemed as if a stone had been rolled
        from his heart since it was no longer needful for him to kill her. And as a young boar just then
        came running by he stabbed it, and cut out its heart and took it to the Queen as proof that the
        child was dead. The cook had to salt this, and <villainization cause="revenge">the wicked Queen ate it, and thought she had
            eaten the heart of Snow-white.</villainization></p> 
    
    <p><autonomy level="damsel">But now the <adjective gender="female">poor child</adjective> was all alone in the great forest, and so
        <adjective gender="female">terrified</adjective> that she looked at every leaf of every tree, and did not know what to do. Then she
        began to run, and ran over sharp stones and through thorns,</autonomy> and the wild beasts ran past her,
        but did her no harm.</p> 
    
    <p><autonomy level="damsel">She ran as long as her feet would go until it was almost evening;</autonomy> then she
        saw a little cottage and went into it to rest herself. Everything in the cottage was small, but
        neater and cleaner than can be told. There was a table on which was a white cover, and seven
        little plates, and on each plate a little spoon; moreover, there were seven little knives and
        forks, and seven little mugs. Against the wall stood seven little beds side by side, and covered
        with snow-white counterpanes.</p> 
    
    <p><autonomy level="damsel"><characteristic depiction="innocent"><adjective gender="female">Little</adjective> Snow-white</characteristic>was so hungry and thirsty that she ate some
        vegetables and bread from each plate and drank a drop of wine out of each mug, for she did not
        wish to take all from one only. Then, as she was so tired, she laid herself down on one of the
        little beds, but none of them suited her; one was too long, another too short, but at last she
        found that the seventh one was right, and so she remained in it, said a prayer and went to
        sleep.</autonomy></p>
    
    <p>When it was quite dark the owners of the cottage came back; they were seven dwarfs who
        dug and delved in the mountains for ore. They lit their seven candles, and as it was now light
        within the cottage they saw that someone had been there, for everything was not in the same
        order in which they had left it.</p> 
    
    <p>The first said, <quote>Who has been sitting on my chair?</quote>
        
        The second, <quote>Who has been eating off my plate?</quote>
        
        The third, <quote>Who has been taking some of my bread?</quote>
        
        The fourth, <quote>Who has been eating my vegetables?</quote>
        
        The fifth, <quote>Who has been using my fork?</quote>
        
        The sixth, <quote>Who has been cutting with my knife?</quote>
        
        The seventh, <quote>Who has been drinking out of my mug?</quote></p>
    
    <p>Then the first looked round and saw that there was a <adjective gender="female">little</adjective> hole on his bed, and he said, <quote>Who has
        been getting into my bed?</quote> The others came up and each called out, <quote>Somebody has been lying in
            my bed too.</quote> But the seventh when he looked at his bed saw <adjective gender="female">little</adjective> Snow-white, who was lying
        asleep therein. And he called the others, who came running up, and they cried out with
        astonishment, and brought their seven little candles and let the light fall on <characteristic depiction="innocent">little
            Snow-white.</characteristic> <quote>Oh, heavens! oh, heavens!</quote> cried they, <quote><characteristic>what a lovely child!</characteristic><!--Add attributes here--></quote> 
        and they were so glad that they did not wake her up, but let her sleep on in the bed. And the seventh dwarf slept with
        his companions, one hour with each, and so got through the night.</p> 
    
    <p>When it was morning <characteristic depiction="innocent">little
        Snow-white</characteristic> awoke, and was frightened when she saw the seven dwarfs. But they were friendly and
        asked her what her name was. <quote>My name is Snow-white,</quote> she answered. <quote>How have you come to our
            house?</quote> said the dwarfs. Then she told them that her step-mother had wished to have her killed,
        but that the huntsman had spared her life, and that she had run for the whole day, until at last
        she had found their dwelling. The dwarfs said, <quote><autonomy level="societal_expectations">If you will take care of our house, cook, make
            the beds, wash, sew, and knit, and if you will keep everything neat and clean, you can stay with
            us and you shall want for nothing.</autonomy></quote> <quote>Yes,</quote> said Snow-white, <quote>with all my heart,</quote> and she stayed
        with them. <autonomy level="societal_expectations">She kept the house in order for them; in the mornings they went to the mountains and
            looked for copper and gold, in the evenings they came back, and then their supper had to be
            ready.</autonomy> The girl was alone the whole day, so the good dwarfs warned her and said, <quote>Beware of your
                step-mother, she will soon know that you are here; be sure to let no one come in.</quote></p>
    <!--With element "autonomy", make sure to add auto_type AND gender attributes-->
    <p><villainization cause="competition">But the Queen, believing that she had eaten Snow-white’s heart, could not but think that she was again
        the first and <adjective gender="female">most beautiful of all</adjective>; and she went to her looking-glass and said— 
        <quote>Looking-glass, Looking-glass, on the wall, Who in this land is the <adjective gender="female">fairest of all</adjective>?</quote>
        and the glass answered—
        <quote>Oh, Queen, thou art fairest of all I see, But over the hills, where the seven dwarfs dwell,
            Snow-white is still alive and well, <characteristic depiction="beauty">And none is so <adjective gender="female">fair</adjective> as she.</characteristic></quote>
        Then she was astounded, for she
        knew that the looking-glass never spoke falsely, and she knew that the huntsman had betrayed
        her, and that <characteristic depiction="innocent">little Snow-white </characteristic>was still alive.</villainization></p> 
    
    <p><villainization cause="revenge">And so she thought and thought again how she
        might kill her, for so long as she was not <characteristic depiction="beauty">the <adjective gender="female">fairest</adjective> in the whole land,</characteristic> envy let her have no
        rest.</villainization> And when she had at last thought of something to do, <characteristic>she painted her face, and dressed
            herself like an <adjective gender="female">old</adjective> peddler-woman,</characteristic> and no one could have known her. In this disguise she went
        over the seven mountains to the seven dwarfs, and knocked at the door and cried, <quote>Pretty things
            to sell, very cheap, very cheap.</quote> <characteristic depiction="innocent">Little Snow-white </characteristic>looked out of the window and called out,
        <quote>Good-day my good woman, what have you to sell?</quote> <quote>Good things, pretty things,</quote> she answered;
        <quote>stay-laces of all colours,</quote> and she pulled out one which was woven of bright-coloured silk. <quote>I
            may let the worthy <characteristic age="old">old woman </characteristic>in,</quote> thought Snow-white, and she unbolted the door and bought the
        pretty laces. <quote>Child,</quote> said the old woman, <quote>what a fright you look; come, I will lace you
            properly for once.</quote> Snow-white <characteristic gender="female" depiction="naivity" age="young">had no suspicio</characteristic>n, but stood before her, and let herself be laced
        with the new laces. But the <villainization cause="jealousy">old woman laced so quickly and so tightly that Snow-white lost her
            breath and fell down as if dead.</villainization><quote><characteristic>Now I am the most beautiful,</characteristic></quote> said the Queen to herself, and
        ran away.</p> 
    
    <p>Not long afterwards, in the evening, the seven dwarfs came home, but how shocked they
        were when they saw their <characteristic depiction="innocent"><adjective gender="female">dear little</adjective> Snow-white</characteristic> lying on the ground, and that she neither
        stirred nor moved, and seemed to be dead. They lifted her up, and, as they saw that she was
        laced too tightly, they cut the laces; then she began to breathe a little, and after a while
        came to life again. When the dwarfs heard what had happened they said, <quote>The <adjective gender="female">old</adjective> peddler-woman
            was no one else than the <villainization cause="unspecified"><adjective gender="female">wicked</adjective> Queen</villainization>; take care and let no one come in when we are not with
            you.</quote></p>
    
    <p><villainization cause="competition">But the <adjective gender="female">wicked</adjective> woman when she had reached home went in front of the glass and asked—
        <quote>Looking-glass, Looking-glass, on the wall, Who in this land is the fairest of all?</quote>
        and it answered as before— 
        <quote>Oh, Queen, thou art <adjective gender="female">fairest</adjective> of all I see, But over the hills, where the
            seven dwarfs dwell, Snow-white is still alive and well, And <characteristic depiction="beauty">none is so <adjective gender="female">fair</adjective> as she.</characteristic></quote></villainization></p>
    
    <p>When she
        heard that, all her blood rushed to her heart with fear, for she saw plainly that <characteristic depiction="innocent"><adjective gender="female">little</adjective>
            Snow-white</characteristic> was again alive. <quote>But now,</quote> she said, <quote><villainization cause="revenge">I will think of something that shall put an
                end to you,</villainization></quote> and by the help of witchcraft, which she understood, <villainization>she made a poisonous comb.</villainization>
        Then she disguised herself and took the shape of another <characteristic age="old">old woman.</characteristic> So she went over the seven
        mountains to the seven dwarfs, knocked at the door, and cried, <quote>Good things to sell, cheap,
            cheap!</quote> <characteristic depiction="innocent">Little Snow-white</characteristic> looked out and said, <quote>Go away; I cannot let any one come in.</quote> <quote>I
                suppose you can look,</quote> said the old woman, and pulled the poisonous comb out and held it up. It
        <characteristic depiction="naivity">pleased the girl so well that she let herself be <adjective gender="female">beguiled</adjective>,</characteristic> and opened the door. When they had
        made a bargain the <adjective gender="female">old</adjective> woman said, <quote>Now I will comb you properly for once.</quote> <characteristic depiction="innocent">Poor little
            Snow-white</characteristic> had no suspicion, and let the old woman do as she pleased, but hardly had <villainization cause="jealousy">she put the
                comb in her hair than the poison in it took effect, and the girl fell down <adjective gender="female">senseless</adjective>.</villainization> <quote><characteristic depiction="beauty">You
                    paragon of beauty,</characteristic></quote> said the <villainization cause="unspecified"><adjective gender="female">wicked</adjective> woman,</villainization> <quote>you are done for now,” and she went away.</quote></p>
    
    <p>But fortunately it was almost evening, when the seven dwarfs came home. When they saw Snow-white
        lying as if dead upon the ground they at once suspected the step-mother, and they looked and
        found the poisoned comb. Scarcely had they taken it out when Snow-white came to herself, and
        told them what had happened. Then they warned her once more to be upon her guard and to open the
        door to no one.</p> 
    
    <p><villainization cause="competition">The Queen, at home, went in front of the glass and said— 
        <quote>Looking-glass, Looking-glass, on the wall, Who in this land is <adjective gender="female">the fairest of all</adjective>?</quote>
        then it answered as before—
        <quote>Oh, Queen, thou art <adjective gender="female">fairest</adjective> of all I see, But over the hills, where the seven dwarfs dwell,
            Snow-white is still alive and well, <characteristic depiction="beauty">And none is so <adjective gender="female">fair</adjective> as she.</characteristic></quote>
        When she heard the glass speak thus she trembled and shook with rage. <quote>Snow-white shall die,</quote> she cried, <quote>even if it costs me
            my life!</quote></villainization></p>
    
    <p><villainization cause="revenge">Thereupon she went into a quite secret, lonely room, where no one ever came, and there
        she made a very poisonous apple. Outside it looked pretty, white with a red cheek, so that
        everyone who saw it longed for it; but whoever ate a piece of it must surely die.</villainization></p> 
    
    <p>When the apple
        was ready she painted her face, and <characteristic char_type="physical">dressed herself up as a country-woman,</characteristic> and so she went over
        the seven mountains to the seven dwarfs. She knocked at the door. Snow-white put her head out of
        the window and said, <quote>I cannot let any one in; the seven dwarfs have forbidden me.</quote> <quote>It is all
            the same to me,</quote> answered the woman, <quote>I shall soon get rid of my apples. There, I will give you
                one.</quote></p>
    
    <p><quote>No,</quote> said Snow-white, <quote>I dare not take anything.</quote> <quote>Are you afraid of poison?</quote> said the
        <adjective gender="female">old</adjective> woman; <quote>look, I will cut the apple in two pieces; you eat the red cheek, and I will eat the
            white.</quote> The apple was so <adjective gender="female">cunningly</adjective> made that only the red cheek was poisoned. Snow-white longed
        for the fine apple, and when she saw that the woman ate part of it <autonomy auto_type="controlled">she could resist no longer,
            and stretched out her hand and took the poisonous half.</autonomy> But hardly had she a bit of it in her
        mouth than she fell down dead. <villainization cause="manipulation">Then the Queen looked at her with a dreadful look, and laughed
            aloud</villainization> and said, <quote><characteristic char_type="physical"><adjective gender="female">White as snow, red as blood, black as ebony-wood!</adjective></characteristic> this time the dwarfs cannot
                wake you up again.</quote></p>
    
    <p><villainization cause="competition">And when she asked of the Looking-glass at home— 
        <quote>Looking-glass, Looking-glass, on the wall, Who in this land is the <adjective gender="female">fairest</adjective> of all?</quote>
        it answered at last— 
        <quote>Oh, Queen, in this land <characteristic depiction="beauty">thou art <adjective gender="female">fairest</adjective> of all.</characteristic></quote>
        Then her <adjective gender="female">envious</adjective> heart had rest, so far as an envious heart can have rest.</villainization></p> 
    
    <p>The dwarfs, when they came home in the evening, found Snow-white
        lying upon the ground; she breathed no longer and was dead. They lifted her up, looked to see
        whether they could find anything poisonous, unlaced her, combed her hair, washed her with water
        and wine, but it was all of no use; the poor child was dead, and remained dead. They laid her
        upon a bier, and all seven of them sat round it and wept for her, and wept three days long.</p> 
    
    <p>Then they were going to bury her, but she still looked as if she were living, and <characteristic char_type="physical">still had her
        <adjective gender="female">pretty red cheeks</adjective>.</characteristic> They said, <quote>We could not bury her in the dark ground,</quote> and they had a
        transparent coffin of glass made, <autonomy level="damsel">so that she could be seen from all sides,</autonomy> and they laid her in
        it, and wrote her name upon it in golden letters, and that she was a king’s daughter. Then they
        put the coffin out upon the mountain, and one of them always stayed by it and watched it. And
        birds came too, and wept for Snow-white; first an owl, then a raven, and last a dove.</p> 
    
    <p>And now Snow-white lay a long, long time in the coffin, and <characteristic char_type="physical">she did not change, but looked as if she
        were asleep; for she was as <adjective gender="female">white as snow, as red as blood, and her hair was as black as ebony.</adjective></characteristic></p>
    
    <p>It happened, however, that a king’s son came into the forest, and went to the dwarfs’ house to
        spend the night. He saw the coffin on the mountain, and the <characteristic depiction="beauty"><adjective gender="female">beautiful</adjective> Snow-white</characteristic> within it, and
        read what was written upon it in golden letters. Then he said to the dwarfs, <autonomy level="male_savior"><quote>Let me have the
            coffin, I will give you whatever you want for it.</quote> But the dwarfs answered, <quote>We will not part
                with it for all the gold in the world.</quote> Then he said, <quote>Let me have it as a gift, for I cannot
                    live without seeing Snow-white. I will honour and prize <autonomy auto_type="controlled" level="damsel" gender="female">her as my dearest possession</autonomy>.</quote> As he
            spoke in this way the good dwarfs took pity upon him, and gave him the coffin.</autonomy></p> 
    
    <p>And now the
        King’s son had it carried away by his servants on their shoulders. And it happened that they
        stumbled over a tree-stump, and with the shock the poisonous piece of apple which Snow-white had
        bitten off came out of her throat. And before long she opened her eyes, lifted up the lid of the
        coffin, sat up, and was once more alive. <quote>Oh, heavens, where am I?</quote> she cried. The King’s son,
        full of joy, said, <autonomy level="male_savior"><quote>You are with me,</quote> and told her what had happened, and said, <quote>I love you more
            than everything in the world; come with me to my father’s palace, you shall be my wife.</quote></autonomy></p>
    
    <p><autonomy level="societal_expectations">And Snow-white was willing, and went with him,</autonomy> and their wedding was held with great show and
        splendour. But Snow-white’s <characteristic><adjective gender="female">wicked</adjective> step-mother</characteristic> was also bidden to the feast. <villainization cause="competition">When she had
            arrayed herself in beautiful clothes she went before the Looking-glass, and said—
            <quote>Looking-glass, Looking-glass, on the wall, Who in this land is the <adjective gender="female">fairest of all</adjective>?</quote>
            the glass answered— 
            <quote>Oh, Queen, of all here the <adjective gender="female">fairest</adjective> art thou, But the <characteristic depiction="beauty"><adjective gender="female">young</adjective> Queen is <adjective gender="female">fairer</adjective> by far </characteristic>as I trow.</quote></villainization></p>
    
    <p>Then the <villainization cause="unspecified"><adjective gender="female">wicked</adjective> woman</villainization> uttered a curse, and was <adjective gender="female">so wretched, so utterly wretched</adjective>, that
        she knew not what to do. At first she would not go to the wedding at all, but she had no peace,
        and must go to see the young Queen. And when she went in she knew Snow-white; and she stood
        still with <villainization cause="jealousy">rage and fear, and could not stir. But iron slippers had already been put upon the
            fire, and they were brought in with tongs, and set before her. Then she was forced to put on the
            red-hot shoes, and dance until she dropped down dead.</villainization></p></story>


