<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../Schemas/grimmprojectschema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<story>
    <title>Rapunzel</title>
    <p> There were once a man and a woman who <characteristic depiction="maternal" gender="female"
            >wished for a child</characteristic>.
        <!-- love the depiction attribute but im not sure if gender is necessary --> At length the
        woman hoped <autonomy level="religious" gender="female">that God was about to grant her
            desire</autonomy>. These people had a little window at the back of their house from
        which a splendid garden could be seen, which was full of the most beautiful flowers and
        herbs. It was, however, surrounded by a high wall, and no one dared to go into it because it
        belonged to an enchantress <!-- can possibly tag this as secluded -->, <autonomy
            level="evil" gender="female">who had great power</autonomy> and was <villainization
            cause="power" gender="female">
            <!-- your tags are good but im not too sure if you have to tag the gender with every element -->dreaded
            by all the world</villainization>. One day the woman was standing by this window and
        looking down into the garden, when <characteristic depiction="beauty" gender="female">she
            saw a bed which was planted with the most beautiful rampion - rapunzel , and it looked
            so fresh and green that she longed for it</characteristic>, and had the greatest desire
        to eat some. This desire increased every day
        <!-- autonomy level controlled (and can maybe comment that she is being specifically controlled by her desire [sexual reference? idk]) -->,
        and as she knew that she could not get any of it, <characteristic char_type="physical"
            gender="female">she quite pined away, and began to look pale and
            miserable</characteristic>.Then her husband was alarmed, and asked, <quote>what ails
            you, dear wife.</quote>
        <quote>Ah,</quote> she replied, <quote>if I can't eat some of the rampion, which is in the
            garden behind our house, I shall die <!-- weak-->.</quote> The man, who loved her
        thought, <autonomy level="male_savior" gender="male">sooner than let your wife die, bring
            her some of the rampion yourself, let it cost what it will</autonomy>. At twilight, he
        clambered down over the wall into the garden of the enchantress ,<autonomy
            level="male_savior" gender="male"> hastily clutched a handful of rampion, and took it to
            his wife</autonomy>. She at once made herself a salad of it, and ate it
            <adjective>greedily</adjective>. It tasted so good to her - so very good, that the next
        day she longed for it three times as much as before. If he was to have any rest, her husband
        must once more descend into the garden. In the gloom of evening, therefore, he let himself
        down again. But when he had clambered down the wall he was terribly afraid, for he saw the
        enchantress standing before him.<quote><villainization cause="revenge" gender="female">How
                can you dare, said she with angry<!-- adjective --> look, descend into my garden and
                steal my rampion like a thief. You shall suffer for it.</villainization></quote>
        <quote>Ah,</quote> answered he, <quote>let mercy take the place of justice, I only made up
            my mind to do it out of necessity. My wife saw your rampion from the window, and felt
            such a longing for it that she would have died if she had not got some to eat." Then the
            enchantress allowed her anger to be softened, and said to him,</quote>
        <quote><villainization cause="revenge" gender="female">if the case be as you say, I will
                allow you to take away with you as much rampion as you will, only I make one
                condition, you must give me the child which your wife will bring into the world.
                    <characteristic depiction="maternal" gender="female"> It shall be well treated,
                    and I will care for it like a mother.</characteristic>"</villainization></quote>
        The man in his terror consented to
        everything<!-- autonomy level controlled (by fear [of the woman]) -->, and when the woman
        was brought to bed, the enchantress appeared at once, gave the child the name of rapunzel ,
            <villainization cause="revenge" gender="female">and took it away with
            her</villainization>.Rapunzel grew into <characteristic depiction="beauty"
            gender="female">the most beautiful child under the sun</characteristic>. When
            <characteristic age="young" gender="female">she was twelve years old</characteristic>,
        the enchantress <autonomy auto_type="controlled" gender="female"><characteristic
                depiction="secluded" gender="female">shut her into a tower, which lay in a forest,
                and had neither stairs nor door, but quite at the top was a little
                window.</characteristic></autonomy> When the enchantress wanted to go in, she placed
        herself beneath it and cried, <quote>rapunzel , rapunzel , let down your hair to me.</quote>
        Rapunzel had <characteristic char_type="physical" gender="female">magnificent long hair,
            fine as spun gold,</characteristic> and when she heard the voice of the enchantress she
        unfastened <characteristic char_type="physical" gender="female">her braided tresses, wound
            them round one of the hooks of the window above, and then the hair fell twenty ells
            down</characteristic>, and the enchantress climbed up by it.</p>
    <p>After a year or two, it came to pass that the king's son rode through the forest and passed
        by the tower.Then he heard a song, which was so charming that he stood still and listened.
        This was rapunzel , who in her solitude<!-- characteristic secluded --> passed her time
            in<characteristic depiction="innocent" gender="female"> letting <characteristic
                depiction="beauty" gender="female">her sweet voice</characteristic>
            resound</characteristic> The king's son wanted to climb up to her, and looked for the
        door of the tower, but none was to be found <!-- male savior!!! -->. He rode home, but the
        singing had so deeply touched his heart, that every day he went out into the forest and
        listened to it.Once when he was thus standing behind a tree, he saw that an enchantress came
        there, and he heard how she cried, <quote>rapunzel , rapunzel , let down your
        hair.</quote></p>
    <p>Then rapunzel let down the braids of her hair, and the enchantress climbed up to her. If that
        is the ladder by which one mounts, I too will try my fortune <!-- clever? -->, said he, and
        the next day when it began to grow dark, he went to the tower and cried, <quote>rapunzel ,
            rapunzel , let down your hair.</quote></p>
    <p> Immediately the hair fell down and the king's son climbed up. At first rapunzel was terribly
        frightened when a man, such as her eyes had never yet beheld <!-- innocent / secluded -->,
        came to her. But the king's son began to talk to her quite like a friend, and told her that
        his heart had been so stirred that it had let him have no rest
        <!-- autonomy controlled (by love) -->, and he<characteristic depiction="beauty"
            gender="female"> had been forced to see her</characteristic>
        <!-- forced is interesting wording, maybe put this as autonomy controlled and then here you can specificy that the gender is male. i don't think its needed everywhere tho -->.
        Then rapunzel lost her fear, and when he asked her if she would take him for her husband,
        and she saw that he was <characteristic age="young" gender="male"
        >young</characteristic><!-- this might be an adjective insteaad of characteristics since its just one word -->
        and <characteristic depiction="beauty" gender="male">handsome</characteristic>, she thought,
        he will love me more than <characteristic age="old" gender="female">old</characteristic>
        dame gothel does <!-- male savior -->. And she said yes, and laid her hand in his. She said,
            <quote>I will willingly go away with you, <autonomy auto_type="free" gender="female">
                but I do not know how to get down.</autonomy>" </quote>
        <quote>Bring with you a skein of silk every time that you come, and I will weave a ladder
            with it, and when <characteristic depiction="domesticity" gender="female">that is ready
                I will descend, and you will take me on your horse</characteristic>.</quote> They
        agreed that until that time he should come to her every evening, for the old <characteristic
            age="old" gender="female">woman</characteristic> came by day. The enchantress remarked
        nothing of this, until once rapunzel said to her, <quote>tell me, dame gothel , how it
            happens that <characteristic char_type="physical" gender="female">you are so much
                heavier</characteristic>
            <!-- LMAO??? --> for me to draw up than the young king's son <!-- naivity prob --> - he
            is with me in a moment.</quote>
        <quote>Ah. You wicked child,</quote> cried the enchantress . <quote>What do I hear you say.
                <villainization cause="revenge" gender="female">I thought <autonomy
                    auto_type="controlled" gender="female">I had separated you from all the world
                    <!-- secluded --></autonomy>, and yet you have deceived
            me.</villainization></quote> In her anger she clutched rapunzel 's <characteristic
            char_type="physical" gender="female">beautiful tresses,</characteristic>
        <autonomy level="evil" gender="female">wrapped them twice round her left hand, seized a pair
            of scissors with the right, and snip, snap,
            <!-- this could be attempts at castration, should comment and maybe tag as sexual rep_type sex? -->
            they were cut off, and the <adjective>lovely</adjective> braids lay on the
            ground.</autonomy>
        <autonomy level="damsel" gender="female"> And she was so pitiless that <characteristic
                depiction="secluded" gender="female">she took poor rapunzel into a desert where she
                had to live in great grief and misery</characteristic></autonomy>.</p>
    <p>On the same day that she cast out rapunzel ,however, the enchantress fastened the braids of
        hair, which she had cut off <!-- clever and manipulation -->, to the hook of the window, and
        when the king's son came and cried, <quote>rapunzel , rapunzel , let down your hair,she let
            the hair down.</quote></p>
    <p>The king's son ascended, but instead of finding his dearest rapunzel , he found the
        enchantress , <characteristic char_type="physical" gender="female">who gazed at him with
            wicked and venomous looks</characteristic>. <quote>Aha</quote>, <autonomy level="evil"
            gender="female">she cried mockingly</autonomy>, <quote>you would fetch your dearest, but
            the <adjective>beautiful</adjective> bird sits no longer singing in the nest.
            <!-- villainization -->The cat has got it, and will scratch out your eyes as well.
                <autonomy auto_type="controlled" gender="female">Rapunzel is lost to you. You will
                never see her again.</autonomy></quote> The king's son was beside himself with pain,
        and in his despair he leapt down from the tower.<characteristic char_type="physical"
            gender="male"> He escaped with his life, but the thorns into which he fell pierced his
            eyes</characteristic>
        <!-- another possible castration representation -->. Then he wandered quite blind about the
        forest, ate nothing but roots and berries, and did naught but lament and weep over the loss
        of his
            <!-- this is interesting, maybe mark as something like weak (idk what we have, look at methodologies --><adjective>dearest
            wife</adjective>. Thus he roamed about in <adjective>misery</adjective> for some years,
        and at length came to the desert where rapunzel , <characteristic depiction="maternal"
            gender="female">with the twins to which she had given birth
            <!-- mark this as childbirth?! -->, a boy and a girl</characteristic>, lived in
        wretchedness <!-- adjective? -->. He heard a voice, and it seemed so familiar to him that he
        went towards it, and when he approached, rapunzel knew him and fell on his neck and wept.Two
        of her tears wetted his eyes and they grew clear again, and he could see with them as
        before.
            <!-- this is honestly interesting because i would say that she's the savior instead of him. mark her as heroin when her tears saved him for sure --><autonomy
            level="male_savior" gender="male">He led her to his kingdom where he was joyfully
            received</autonomy>, and they lived for a long time afterwards, happy and contented <!-- adjective? -->.</p>
</story>
