<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<story>
    <title>Rapunzel</title>
    <p> There were once a <characteristic char_type="male">man</characteristic> and a
            <characteristic char_type="woman"
        >woman</characteristic><!-- i don't think you need to markup any instance of man/woman as a char_type, but rather i'd use it if they mentioned that a certain attribute was associated with a specific man/woman to act as a lens -->
        wished for a
        child<!-- i would markup that they wished for a child as characteristic depiction of maternity -->.
        At length the <characteristic char_type="woman">woman</characteristic> hoped that God was
        about to grant her
        desire.<!-- mention of god is definitely religious (attribute under element autonomy) -->
        These people had a little window at the back of their house from which a splendid garden
        could be seen, which was full of the most beautiful flowers and herbs. It was, however,
        surrounded by a high wall, and no one dared to go into it because it belonged to an
        enchantress , <autonomy auto_type="evil">who had great power</autonomy> and was
            <origin>dreaded by all the
        world</origin><!-- instead of origin element i would mark this as villainization, could add attribute power? -->.
        One day the <characteristic char_type="woman">woman</characteristic> was standing by this
        window and looking down into the garden, when she saw a bed which was planted with the most
            <adjective>beautiful</adjective> rampion - rapunzel , and it looked so fresh and green
        that she longed for
        it<!-- possibly characteristic depiction of beauty? her attraction to it is intersting -->,
        and had <desire>the greatest desire to eat some. This desire increased every day,</desire>
        and as she knew that she could not get any of it, she quite pined away, and began to look
        pale and miserable.<!-- depiction of dependent, weak and/or submissive? --> Then her husband
        was alarmed, and asked, <quote>"what ails you, dear wife."</quote>
        <quote>"Ah, she replied, if I can't eat some of the rampion, which is in the garden behind
            our house, I shall die."</quote> The <characteristic char_type="man"
            >man</characteristic>, who loved her<!--this is example of char_type for a man-->,
        thought, sooner than let your wife die, bring her some of the rampion yourself, let it cost
        what it will<!-- male savior! -->. At twilight, he clambered down over the wall into the
        garden of the enchantress , hastily clutched a handful of rampion, and took it to his wife
        <!-- male power! of course he's the one who can do this and not the woman herself -->. She
        at once made herself a salad of it, and ate it
        greedily<!-- greedily is an important adjective here to describe the mother and maternity itself -->.
        It tasted so good to her - so very good, that the next day she longed for it three times as
        much as before<!-- woman as greedy, selfish -->. If he was to have any rest, her husband
        must once more descend into the garden. In the gloom of evening, therefore, he let himself
        down again. But when he had clambered down the wall he was terribly afraid, for he saw the
        enchantress standing before him<!-- male as being submissive? interesting -->.
                <quote><villanization cause="revenge">"How can you dare, said she with angry look,
                descend into my garden and steal my rampion like a thief. You shall suffer for
                it."</villanization></quote> Ah, answered he, "let mercy take the place of justice,
        I only made up my mind to do it out of necessity<!-- not truly devoted! men smh -->. My wife
        saw your rampion from the window, and felt such a longing for it that she would have died if
        she had not got some to eat." Then the enchantress allowed her anger to be softened, and
        said to him,<quote>
            <villianization cause="revenge">"if the case be as you say, I will allow you to take
                away with you as much rampion as you will, only I make one condition, you must give
                me the child which your wife will bring into the world. <characteristic
                    char_type="maternal"> It shall be well treated, and I will care for it like a
                    mother.</characteristic>"<!-- this is an interesting representation of maternity, though, since it's lowkey abduction... --></villianization></quote>
        The <characteristic char_type="man">man</characteristic> in his terror consented to
        everything<!-- male is the one without autonomy here -->, and when the <characteristic
            char_type="woman">woman</characteristic> was brought to bed, the enchantress appeared at
        once, gave the child the name of rapunzel , and took it away with
        her<!-- villainization? -->. Rapunzel grew into <characteristic depiction="beauty">the most
            beautiful child under the sun</characteristic>. When <characteristic age="young">she was
            twelve years old</characteristic>, the enchantress <autonomy auto_type="controlled">shut
            her into a tower, which lay in a forest<!-- secluded -->, and had neither stairs nor
            door, but quite at the top was a little window.</autonomy> When the enchantress wanted
        to go in, she placed herself beneath it and cried, <quote>" rapunzel , rapunzel , let down
            your hair to me."</quote>
        <!-- this indicates that rapunzel doesn't really have autonomy either -->Rapunzel had
            <characteristic char_type="physical">magnificent long hair, fine as spun
            gold,</characteristic> and when she heard the voice of the enchantress she unfastened
            <characteristic char_type="physical">her braided tresses, wound them round one of the
            hooks of the window above, and then the hair fell twenty ells down</characteristic>, and
        the enchantress climbed up by it.</p>
    <p>After a year or two, it came to pass that the king's son rode through the forest and passed
        by the tower. <lovestruck><!-- lovestruck isn't an element in relax ng --> Then he heard a
            song, which was so charming that he stood still and listened. This was rapunzel , who in
            her solitude passed her time in<characteristic char_type="innocence"> letting her sweet
                voice resound<!-- this is also beauty -->.</characteristic> The king's son wanted to
            climb up to her, and looked for the door of the tower, but none was to be
            found<!-- could mark this as male power/autonomy level being controlled for rapunzel -->.
            He rode home, but the singing had so deeply touched his heart, that every day he went
            out into the forest and listened to it.</lovestruck> Once when he was thus standing
        behind a tree, he saw that an enchantress came there, and he heard how she cried, <quote>"
            rapunzel , rapunzel , let down your hair."</quote></p>
    <p>Then rapunzel let down the braids of her hair, and the enchantress climbed up to her. If that
        is the ladder by which one mounts, I too will try my fortune, said he, and the next day when
        it began to grow dark, he went to the tower and cried, <quote>" rapunzel , rapunzel , let
            down your hair."<!-- manipulation from him --></quote></p> Immediately the hair fell
    down and the king's son climbed up. <p>At first rapunzel was terribly frightened when a
            <characteristic char_type="man"
        >man</characteristic><!-- i wouldn't mark this is char_type since they don't describe him -->,
        such as her eyes had never yet beheld, came to her. <lovestruck>But the king's son began to
            talk to her quite like a friend, and told her that his heart had been so stirred that it
            had let him have no rest, and he had been forced to see
            her<!-- depiction of her beauty -->. Then rapunzel lost her fear, and when he asked her
            if she would take him for her husband, and she saw that he was <characteristic
                age="young">young</characteristic> and
            <adjective>handsome</adjective><!-- this talks ab his beauty -->, she thought, he will
            love me more than <characteristic age="old">old</characteristic> dame gothel
            does<!-- male savior, saving from mother specifically, which is intersting -->. And she
            said yes, and laid her hand in his.</lovestruck> She said, <quote>"I will willingly go
            away with you, <autonomy auto_type="controlled"
                ><!-- i would actually say that language "willingly" suggests freedom (even if she isn't actually free) -->but
                I do not know how to get down.</autonomy>" </quote>
        <quote>"Bring with you a skein of silk every time that you come, and I will weave a ladder
            with it, and when that is ready I will descend, and you will take me on your
            horse."</quote><!-- domesticity --> They agreed that until that time he should come to
        her every evening, for the old <characteristic char_type="woman"
        >woman</characteristic><!-- if you were to mark this i would use age attribute old instead of woman -->
        came by day. The enchantress remarked nothing of this, until once rapunzel said to her,
            <quote>"tell me, dame gothel , how it happens that <characteristic char_type="physical"
                >you are so much heavier</characteristic> for me to draw up than the young king's
            son - he is with me in a moment."</quote>
        <quote>"Ah. You wicked child,"</quote> cried the enchantress . <quote>"What do I hear you
            say. <villianization cause="revenge">I thought I had separated you from all the
                world<!-- separating from all the world is controlled in terms of autonomy and also maternal depictions -->,
                and yet you have deceived me.</villianization>"</quote> In her anger she clutched
        rapunzel 's <characteristic char_type="physical">beautiful tresses,</characteristic>
        <autonomy auto_type="evil">wrapped them twice round her left hand, seized a pair of scissors
            with the right, and snip, snap, they were cut off, and the <adjective>lovely</adjective>
            braids lay on the ground.</autonomy>
        <autonomy auto_type="damsel"> And she was so pitiless that she took poor rapunzel into a
            desert where she had to live in great grief and misery.<!-- secluded --></autonomy></p>
    <p>On the same day that she cast out rapunzel , <plotting>however, the enchantress fastened the
            braids of hair, which she had cut off, to the hook of the
        window,</plotting><!-- plotting is not an element in methodologies --> and when the king's
        son came and cried, <quote> "rapunzel , rapunzel , let down your hair,she let the hair
            down."</quote></p>
    <p>The king's son ascended, but instead of finding his dearest rapunzel , he found the
        enchantress , <characteristic auto_type="physical">who gazed at him with wicked and venomous
            looks</characteristic>. <quote>"Aha"</quote>, <autonomy auto_type="evil">she cried
            mockingly</autonomy>, <quote>"you would fetch your dearest, but the
                <adjective>beautiful</adjective> bird sits no longer singing in the nest.The cat has
            got it, and will scratch out your eyes as
            well<!-- this an is interesting metaphor that i might just comment on-->. Rapunzel is
            lost to you. You will never see her again."<!-- autonomy level controlled --></quote>
        The king's son <pain>was beside himself with pain, and in his despair he leapt down from the
            tower.</pain><!-- pain is not an element in methodologies --> He escaped with his life,
        but the thorns into which he fell pierced his eyes. <!-- could just mark this as physical action in depiction, cursed to no longer see beauty basically -->
        <sad>Then he wandered quite blind about the forest, ate nothing but roots and berries, and
            did naught but lament and weep over the loss of his dearest
            wife.<!-- dearest wife is an adjective that should be marked up --></sad><!-- sad is not an element in methodologies-->
        Thus he roamed about in misery<!-- misery is important adjective too --> for some years, and
        at length came to the desert where rapunzel , with the twins to which she had given birth, a
        boy and a girl, lived in wretchedness<!-- maternal depiction -->. He heard a voice, and it
        seemed so familiar to him that he went towards it, and when he approached, rapunzel knew him
        and fell on his neck and wept. <magic>Two of her tears wetted his eyes and they grew clear
            again, and he could see with them as
            before.<!-- characteristic depiction, possibly maternal? could elave a comment explaining that woman is associated with healing here --></magic><!-- magic is not an element in methodologies -->
        He led her to his kingdom where he was joyfully received, and they lived for a long time
        afterwards, happy and contented.<!-- male savior --></p>
</story>
