<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../Schemas/grimmprojectschema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<story story_title='redridinghood' version='grimm'>
    <title>Little Red-Cap</title>
    <p>Once upon a time there was a <characteristic depiction="innocent"><adjective>dear
                little</adjective> girl</characteristic> who was <characteristic
            char_type="physical">loved by every one who looked at her</characteristic>, but most of
        all by her grandmother, and <characteristic depiction="maternal"
            ><!-- maternal sacrifice and expectation of mothers -->there was nothing that she would
            not have given to the child</characteristic>. Once she gave her a <reproduction
            rep_type="menstruation">little cap of red velvet</reproduction>, which <characteristic
            char_type="physical">suited her so
        well</characteristic><!-- inevitability of menstruation/female destiny -->that she would
        never wear anything else; so she was always called “<adjective>Little</adjective>
        Red-Cap.”</p>
    <p>One day her mother said to her, “Come, <adjective>Little</adjective> Red-Cap, here is a piece
        of cake and a bottle of wine; <autonomy auto_type="controlled" level="societal_expectations"
            >take them to your grandmother</autonomy>, <characteristic age="old"><autonomy
                auto_type="controlled">
                <!-- autonomy controlled b/c grandma is dependent -->she is ill and
            weak</autonomy></characteristic>, and they will do her good. Set out before it gets hot,
        and when you are going, <characteristic depiction="innocent">
            <autonomy level="societal_expectations">walk nicely and quietly and do not run off the
                path</autonomy></characteristic>, or you may fall and break the bottle, and then
            <autonomy level="societal_expectations">your grandmother will get
        nothing</autonomy><!-- expectation that women, of any age, will provide for others -->; and
        when you go into her room, <autonomy level="societal_expectations"> don’t forget to say,
            ‘Good-morning,’</autonomy> and don’t peep into every corner before you do it.”</p>
    <p><quote><characteristic depiction="innocent">I will take great care,</characteristic></quote>
        said <adjective>Little</adjective> Red-Cap to her mother, and gave her hand on it.</p>
    <!-- eager to help! -->
    <p>The <characteristic age="old" depiction="secluded">grandmother lived out in the wood, half a
            league from the village</characteristic>, and just as <adjective>Little</adjective>
        Red-Cap entered the wood, a wolf met her. Red-Cap did not know <villainization gender="male"
            >what a <adjective>wicked</adjective> creature he was</villainization>, and
            <characteristic depiction="naivity">was not at all afraid of him</characteristic>.</p>
    <p><quote>Good-day, <adjective>Little</adjective> Red-Cap,</quote> said he.
                <quote><characteristic depiction="innocent">Thank you kindly,
            wolf.</characteristic></quote></p>
    <p><quote>Whither away so early, <adjective>Little</adjective> Red-Cap?</quote>
        <quote>To my grandmother’s.</quote>
        <quote>What have you got in your apron?</quote>
        <quote><characteristic depiction="domesticity">Cake and wine; yesterday was
                baking-day</characteristic>, so <adjective>poor sick</adjective> grandmother is to
            have something good, to make her stronger.</quote>
        <quote>Where does your grandmother live, <adjective>Little</adjective> Red-Cap?</quote></p>
    <p><quote><characteristic depiction="naivity">A good quarter of a league farther on in the wood;
                her house stands under the three large oak-trees, the nut-trees are just below; you
                surely must know it,</characteristic></quote> replied <adjective>Little</adjective>
        Red-Cap.</p>
    <p>The wolf thought to himself, <quote><characteristic depiction="innocent" age="young">What a
                    <adjective>tender young</adjective> creature! what a <characteristic age="old"
                        ><adjective>nice plump</adjective> mouthful—<autonomy auto_type="controlled"
                        >she will be better to eat</autonomy> than the <adjective>old</adjective>
                    woman</characteristic></characteristic>.<!-- belief that older women are past fruition and no longer valuable; and thus are rotten! -->
            I must act craftily, so as to catch both.</quote> So he walked for a short time by the
        side of <adjective>Little</adjective> Red-Cap, and then he said, <quote>See
                <adjective>Little</adjective> Red-Cap, how pretty the flowers are about
                here—<villainization cause="manipulation">why do you not look
                round?</villainization> I believe, too, that you do not hear how sweetly the little
            birds are singing; you walk gravely along as if you were going to school, while
            everything else out here in the wood is merry.</quote></p>
    <p><adjective>Little</adjective> Red-Cap raised her eyes, and when she saw the sunbeams dancing
        here and there through the trees, and pretty flowers growing everywhere, she thought,
                <quote><characteristic depiction="innocent">Suppose I take grandmother a fresh
                nosegay; that would please her too</characteristic>. It is so early in the day that
            I shall still get there in good time;</quote> and <characteristic depiction="innocent"
            >so she ran from the path into the wood to look for flowers. And <characteristic
                depiction="naivity">whenever she had picked one, she fancied that she saw a still
                prettier one farther on, and ran after it, and so got deeper and deeper into the
                wood.</characteristic></characteristic></p>
    <p>Meanwhile the wolf ran straight to the grandmother’s house and knocked at the door.</p>
    <p><quote>Who is there?</quote></p>
    <p><quote>Little Red-Cap,</quote> replied the wolf. <quote>She is bringing cake and wine; open
            the door.</quote></p>
    <p><quote>Lift the latch,</quote> called out the grandmother, <quote><characteristic age="old">
                <autonomy auto_type="controlled">I am too <adjective>weak</adjective>, and cannot
                    get
            up.</autonomy><!-- old and thus dependent on others! --></characteristic></quote></p>
    <p><villainization gender="male">The wolf lifted the latch, the door flew open, and without
            saying a word he went straight to the grandmother’s bed, and devoured
            her</villainization>. Then <villainization cause="manipulation">he put on her clothes,
            dressed himself in her cap, laid himself in bed and drew the
        curtains.</villainization></p>
    <p><characteristic depiction="naivity">
            <characteristic depiction="innocent"><adjective>Little</adjective> Red-Cap, however, had
                been running about picking flowers, and when she had gathered so many that she could
                carry no more, she remembered her grandmother, and set out on the way to
                her.</characteristic>
        </characteristic></p>
    <p>She was surprised to find the cottage-door standing open, and when she went into the room,
        she had such a <adjective>strange</adjective> feeling that she said to herself, <quote>Oh
            dear! how uneasy I feel to-day, and at other times <characteristic depiction="maternal"
                >I like being with grandmother so
            much</characteristic><!-- female intuition? -->.</quote> She called out, <quote>Good
            morning,</quote> but received no answer; so she went to the bed and drew back the
        curtains. There lay her grandmother with her cap pulled far over her face, and looking very
        strange.</p>
    <p><characteristic depiction="naivity"><quote>Oh! grandmother,</quote> she said, <quote>what big
                ears you have!</quote>
            <quote>The better to hear you with, my child,</quote> was the reply. <quote>But,
                grandmother, what big eyes you have!</quote> she said. <quote>The better to see you
                with, my dear.</quote>
            <quote>But, grandmother, what large hands you have!</quote>
            <quote>The better to hug you with.</quote>
            <quote>Oh! but, grandmother, what a terrible big mouth you have!</quote>
            <quote>The better to eat you with!</quote></characteristic></p>
    <p>And scarcely had the wolf said this, than <villainization gender="male">with one bound he was
            out of bed and swallowed up Red-Cap</villainization>.</p>
    <p><villainization gender="male"><characteristic gender="male" depiction="naivity">When the wolf
                had appeased his appetite, he lay down again in the bed, fell asleep and began to
                snore very loud</characteristic></villainization>. <autonomy level="male_savior">The
            huntsman was just passing the house, and thought to himself, <quote>How the old woman is
                snoring! I must just see if she wants anything.</quote></autonomy> So he went into
        the room, and when he came to the bed, he saw that the wolf was lying in it.
                <quote><autonomy level="religious">Do I find thee here, thou old
            sinner!</autonomy></quote> said he. <quote>I have long sought thee!</quote> Then
            <characteristic depiction="clever" gender="male">just as he was going to fire at him, it
            occurred to him that the wolf might have devoured the grandmother</characteristic>, and
        that <autonomy level="male_savior">she might still be saved</autonomy>, so he did not fire,
        but <reproduction rep_type="childbirth">took a pair of scissors, and began to cut open the
            stomach of the sleeping wolf. When he had made two snips, he saw the little Red-Cap
            shining, and then he made two snips more, and the <adjective>little girl</adjective>
            sprang out</reproduction>, crying, <quote><reproduction rep_type="childbirth"> Ah, how
                frightened I have been! How dark it was inside the
            wolf;</reproduction><!-- possible reading of sex/rebirth? --></quote> and <reproduction
            rep_type="sex">after that the <adjective>aged grandmother</adjective> came out alive
            also, but scarcely able to
        breathe</reproduction><!-- perhaps reproduction? her being able to breath is interesting, maybe sex? going along the grain that she's past sexuality? -->.
            <characteristic depiction="clever">Red-Cap, however, quickly fetched
                <adjective>great</adjective> stones with which they filled the wolf’s
            body</characteristic>, and when he awoke, he wanted to run away, but the stones were so
        heavy that he fell down at once, and fell dead.</p>
    <p>Then all three were delighted. The huntsman drew off the wolf’s skin and went home with it;
        the grandmother ate the cake and drank the wine which Red-Cap had brought, and revived, but
        Red-Cap<!-- no longer being called 'little' red cap --> thought to herself,
                <quote><characteristic depiction="domesticity">
                <autonomy level="societal_expectations">As long as I live, I will never by myself
                    leave the path, to run into the wood, when my <characteristic
                        depiction="maternal">mother has forbidden me to do
                        so<!-- mother as demanding figure, influential --></characteristic>.</autonomy></characteristic></quote></p>
    <p><!-- if we read this as maternal, is she swearing off sex forever? is that 'the path'? -->It
        is also related that once when Red-Cap was again taking cakes to the <adjective>old
            grandmother</adjective>, <reproduction rep_type="sex">another wolf spoke to her, and
            tried to entice her from the path. <characteristic depiction="clever"> Red-Cap, however,
                was on her guard, and went straight forward on her
            way</characteristic><!-- learned her lesson, interesting; opposite of naivity -->, and
            told her grandmother that she had met the wolf, and that he had said
                <quote>good-morning</quote> to her, but with such a wicked look in his eyes, that
                <villainization gender="male">if they had not been on the public road she was
                certain he would have eaten her up</villainization>. <quote>Well,</quote> said the
            grandmother, <quote>we will shut the door, that he may not come
            in.</quote></reproduction><!-- sex --> Soon afterwards the wolf knocked, and cried,
            <quote>Open the door, grandmother, I am little Red-Cap, and am fetching you some
            cakes.</quote> But they did not speak, or open the door, so the grey-beard stole twice
        or thrice round the house, and <villainization gender="male" cause="sex">at last jumped on
            the roof, intending to wait until Red-Cap went home in the evening, and then to steal
            after her and devour her in the darkness</villainization>. But <characteristic
            depiction="protective"><!-- protective AS maternal! also, protecting from sex! -->the
            grandmother saw what was in his thoughts</characteristic>. In front of the house was a
        great stone trough, so she said to the child, <quote>Take the pail, Red-Cap; <characteristic
                depiction="domesticity">I made some sausages yesterday</characteristic>, so carry
            the water in which I boiled them to the trough.</quote> Red-Cap carried until the great
        trough was quite full. Then <characteristic depiction="naivity" gender="male">the smell of
            the sausages reached the wolf, and he sniffed and peeped down, and at last stretched out
            his neck so far that he could no longer keep his footing and began to slip, and slipped
            down from the roof straight into the great trough, and was
        drowned</characteristic><!-- male hunger always being the death of them (sexual or physical) -->.
        But <characteristic depiction="innocent">Red-Cap went joyously home, and never did anything
            to harm any one</characteristic>.</p>
</story>
